<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<add>
   <doc>
      <field name="abstract">He risked everything to free his nation. Now venture into the incredible life and legacy of Paul Revere the master silversmith who forever change the course of American history. Every child knows of Revere's thrilling "midnight ride" but beyond the folklore was a man at the center of a revolution. Although he is one of the country's first folk heroes--inspiring Longfellow's famous 1861 poem--few people realize that Revere also led the Sons of Liberty risked death as a courier and spy helped organize the Boston Tea Party and used his smithery skills to engrave powerful propaganda that enraged British rulers. BIOGRAPHY presents a rousingly unique look at the famed patriot chronicling his service as a Continental Army colonel in the war--and beyond--to his prosperous life as an early American industrialist.</field>
      <field name="asp_community">American History</field>
      <field name="asp_group">History</field>
      <field name="asp_group">American Studies</field>
      <field name="asp_oclc">677926407</field>
      <field name="asp_release_date">2011-10-03T12:52:11Z</field>
      <field name="asp_tertiary_community">Colonial Era (1650-1765)</field>
      <field name="asp_tertiary_community">Revolutionary Era (1765-1789)</field>
      <field name="bibliographic_summary">Video Work: Paul Revere: The Midnight Rider</field>
      <field name="catalog_number">AAE-71833</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456189</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456196</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456199</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456206</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456210</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456215</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456218</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|456224</field>
      <field name="communityfilter">american-history</field>
      <field name="content_en">&lt;asp id="d1000993020" author="" lang="English" lld="" isbn="" lccn="" fd="DORP" lp="Y"&gt;&lt;p&gt;TRANSCRIPT OF VIDEO FILE:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;______________________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;BEGIN TRANSCRIPT:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;Biography A&amp;E Biography&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:00:20]Hello! I'm &lt;pe&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/pe&gt;, welcome to Biography. [00:00:25]Most of us probably first heard his name back in grammar school, [00:00:30]&lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, the midnight rider of the American revolution. Well, [00:00:35]what we learned about &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; back then was probably more myth than [00:00:40]fact. The real &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; did not act alone. [00:00:45]He was an ordinary man as flawed as he was heroic. [00:00:50]But he was a committed patriot, caught up in the excitement of an age when the term "revolution" [00:00:55]was being defined.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:01:00]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:01:05]Listen my children and you shall hear of the midnight [00:01:10]ride of &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Jayne E. Triber Ph.D&lt;/pe&gt;/Revere Biographer&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; When people talk about [00:01:15]&lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, the first thing they talk about is the midnight ride, and they'll usually kind of laugh and say: "The British are [00:01:20]coming, the British are coming."&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; One, if by [00:01:25]land and two if by sea and I on the [00:01:30]opposite shore will be.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/pe&gt; Coordinator of Research Paul Revere House&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; The primary myth that's attached to &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; is [00:01:35]that he was waiting across the river for the signals in the Old North Church Tower. That's the scene which was engraved in everyone's [00:01:40]memory that comes from &lt;pe&gt;Henry Wadsworth Longfellow's&lt;/pe&gt; poem. It's a dramatic scene and it never occurred.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:01:45]So through the night rode &lt;pe&gt;Paul [00:01:50]Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, and so through the night went his cry of alarm, to every [00:01:55]Middlesex village and farm.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;&lt;/sp&gt; It was &lt;pe&gt;Henry Wadsworth [00:02:00]Longfellow's&lt;/pe&gt; poem in &lt;da&gt;1861&lt;/da&gt; that really made &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; famous. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; became kind of a [00:02:05]national folk hero, and the degree to which he became a national folk hero was actually even a little [00:02:10]hard to explain, we can't even really explain that. It's just caught people's imagination, this messenger [00:02:15]rider.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;[00:02:20]&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;PAUL REVERE&lt;/pe&gt;: The Midnight Rider&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:02:30]The story of the real &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; begins in colonial &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, [00:02:35]&lt;da&gt;1715&lt;/da&gt;. When a 13-year-old boy of French Huguenot origin stepped off the boat [00:02:40]that had carried him from his native country to the new world of &lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt;. Sent by his [00:02:45]family to seek his fortune alone, &lt;pe&gt;Apollos Rivoire&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; father, [00:02:50]was bound by a 10-year apprenticeship to Boston goldsmith &lt;pe&gt;John Coney&lt;/pe&gt;. From the highly [00:02:55]skilled &lt;pe&gt;Coney&lt;/pe&gt; he learned one of the most elite trades of the artisan class.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:03:00]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; father was in fact quite lucky in a sense. Goldsmithing [00:03:05]was the best trade to be in. Ah, there was a very definite hierarchical situation in the, in [00:03:10]the ranks of crafts people in those days. Some trades were definitely better than others. Ah, goldsmiths were near the [00:03:15]top, ah, cobblers and shoemakers were near the bottom and others were in between. By the [00:03:20]late &lt;da&gt;1720's&lt;/da&gt; and by the time he married his ah, married his wife &lt;pe&gt;Deborah Hitchbourn&lt;/pe&gt;, he apparently [00:03:25]was a, an operating goldsmith with his own shop.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; Changing [00:03:30]his name to the Anglicized &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, the former &lt;pe&gt;Rivoire&lt;/pe&gt;opened a [00:03:35]small business in &lt;pl&gt;Boston's&lt;/pl&gt; North End where in &lt;da&gt;1734&lt;/da&gt; his first [00:03:40]son &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere Jr.&lt;/pe&gt; was born.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:03:45]We know certain things about &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; early life ah, in some detail. He received what was known as a riding [00:03:50]school education, which was essentially elementary school education. And then he apprenticed with his father in his father's [00:03:55]goldsmith shop and they were long days. Basically, craftsmen work from dawn to dusk.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/pe&gt; Professor of History Boston College&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:04:00]He was a serious, hardworking young man. He attend [00:04:05]the church every Sabbath. Heard the messages of the [00:04:10]clerics. All of which emphasized hard work and need to [00:04:15]get ahead in the world, but also the need to help the community. [00:04:20]I think that was really a model for &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; life. I mean, he certainly committed [00:04:25]himself to getting ahead individually, but he also was committed to the [00:04:30]community.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; and his [00:04:35]seven younger siblings grew up in the rough and ready North End of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:04:40]It's very crowded area, ah, on the one hand you had the &lt;pe&gt;Reveres&lt;/pe&gt; [00:04:45]living ah, in, in rented houses but in the same neighborhood, you had elegant mansions. [00:04:50]So as a young boy and throughout his life, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; couldn't help but be aware that people live [00:04:55]differently. That the wealthy people, the gentlemen wear powdered wigs and ah, their clothing was [00:05:00]colorful. It was imported from &lt;pl&gt;England&lt;/pl&gt;, whereas artisans wore leather aprons and [00:05:05]breeches and home-spun shirts. You could immediately tell someone's class by what they [00:05:10]wore or what their hair looked like and how they spoke.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; Class distinctions [00:05:15]were very real in those days. Society in those days could be described as having three overall [00:05:20]ranks. You have the better sort, you have the middle sort and you have the lesser sort, and &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was in the middle sort. [00:05:25]Although &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; father did achieve a certain amount of success as a goldsmith, I think because he was of [00:05:30]French ancestry, he may have had a little bit of trouble getting business.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:05:35]In &lt;da&gt;1754&lt;/da&gt;, when &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was 19, [00:05:40]his father passed away, leaving &lt;pe&gt;Paul&lt;/pe&gt; his trade, his good name [00:05:45]but little material support that would help him provide for his family. He was a very [00:05:50]young man thrust into a breadwinner's role.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:05:55]Then there was an intervening factor which was the French and Indian War. And at age 19 [00:06:00]he was appointed an officer in an expedition that went ah, to what is now upper &lt;pl&gt;New York State&lt;/pl&gt; to [00:06:05]try to capture a small French port. And basically the troops marched out. They [00:06:10]sat around a camp for a while, they got sick a lot, many of them died from diseases. Then they marched back to &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;. [00:06:15]And this was kind of &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; introduction to the military life. What I think is important is the fact that [00:06:20]being appointed an officer at such a young age he must have shown some leadership ability [00:06:25]that the people who appointed him would have seen, particularly since he was artisan class boy.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:06:30]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; When &lt;pe&gt;Paul [00:06:35]Revere&lt;/pe&gt; returned from the war, those leadership abilities would bring him to the attention of the future leaders [00:06:40]of the American revolution.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:06:45]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:06:55]By the &lt;da&gt;1760's&lt;/da&gt; colonial &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; was a city [00:07:00]in transition. In its North End, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; had built up a [00:07:05]fairly steady business as a silversmith or master goldsmith, the more accurate term. [00:07:10]He had married &lt;pe&gt;Sarah Orne&lt;/pe&gt;, an artisan's daughter and was raising the many [00:07:15]children he had fathered with her. But with &lt;pl&gt;England&lt;/pl&gt; taxing American colonists to [00:07:20]pay off for enormous French and Indian War debt, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, like many Bostonians, [00:07:25]was beginning to feel the stirrings of rebellion.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/pe&gt; Professor of History Boston College&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:07:30]The &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; in which &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; lived, the &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; where the revolutionary movement began, [00:07:35]was a society that was in the grips [00:07:40]of a recession from &lt;da&gt;1700&lt;/da&gt; to a roughly &lt;da&gt;1770&lt;/da&gt;. The number of [00:07:45]people without property, the number of people on the bottom of the economic ladder had doubled [00:07:50]in &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, but &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; himself prospered, and the middling class[00:07:55]of people were prospering. They were conscious of the fact that British policies [00:08:00]were squeezing the economy in a way in which they resented, [00:08:05]ways which too much restricted what people could do and therefore how they could [00:08:10]uhm, move themselves up in the economic ladder.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Jayne E. Triber Ph.D&lt;/pe&gt;/Revere Biographer&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; What drew [00:08:15]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; to the revolutionary cause, I think we have to look at his economic condition. In the early [00:08:20]&lt;da&gt;1760's&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; had a thriving business. He was making buttons and buckles for artisans. [00:08:25]He was making spoons and teapots for Boston's merchant elite&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/pe&gt; Coordinator of Research &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; House&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:08:30]He expected ah as a craftsman to cater to the wealthier people in &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, particularly [00:08:35]since it was the very wealthy who could afford the expensive tea sets and salvers which the [00:08:40]goldsmiths made their greatest profits on. A tea set in those days, a complete tea set could cost half the price of a [00:08:45]house.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; All of a sudden Britain decides to pay off a huge war debt [00:08:50]by imposing various tax-raising measures, including the Stamp Act. [00:08:55]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; realized that this will impact his business negatively. Not so much [00:09:00]directly but if merchants and lawyers are affected they certainly wouldn't have the money to buy a [00:09:05]teapot from &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;. I think what he saw in &lt;da&gt;1765&lt;/da&gt; was a [00:09:10]threat to his aspirations for the future.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:09:15]To scrape through the depression, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; turned to moonlighting in other trades [00:09:20]to keep his growing family fed.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; One was engraving, [00:09:25]which allowed him in lean times to do things like in engrave bookplates or business cards for people. [00:09:30]He learned dentistry. He made false teeth and he advertised that they looks, looked [00:09:35]as good as the natural. He made no claim you could eat with them, but he said they look very good.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:09:40]Even as he struggled to make a living, [00:09:45]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; growing interest in the revolutionary cause was fueled by his involvement in the [00:09:50]Brotherhood of Freemasons.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:09:55]To be a mason it didn't matter ah, what your rank was in society, whether you were a shoemaker [00:10:00]or a gentleman. If you were a person of honor and integrity you could become a mason. [00:10:05]Through masonry, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; got the chance to uhm, exercise leadership [00:10:10]in a society which ordinarily wouldn't have allowed him the opportunity as master goldsmith. [00:10:15]That allowed him a stage, an arena to test himself as a leader, and [00:10:20]I think that in turn showed the leaders of Boston's revolution: this is the man that they could rely [00:10:25]upon. He had a certain amount of status among Boston's artisans and mariners.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:10:30]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; leadership abilities [00:10:35]first caught the attention of his masonic lodge brother &lt;pe&gt;Dr. Joseph Warren&lt;/pe&gt;, 1 of [00:10:40]the leading forces of the "Sons of Liberty". Through &lt;pe&gt;Warren&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was [00:10:45]brought into the inner circles of the growing patriot movement. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; had none of the [00:10:50]education, polish or oratory skills of the gentlemen revolutionaries [00:10:55]but &lt;pe&gt;Warren&lt;/pe&gt; recognized that &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; could prove valuable to the movement in other [00:11:00]ways.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; participation in the revolutionary movement was crucial. The working classes in particular looked to him for [00:11:10]leadership, uhm, that was &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; role, uhm, to act as a liaison between [00:11:15]those working class groups and other more ah, [00:11:20]visible public figures like &lt;pe&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/pe&gt; or &lt;pe&gt;John Hancock&lt;/pe&gt; or &lt;pe&gt;John Adams&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:11:25]He also had specific skills. As a [00:11:30]silversmith, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; also engraved his work. He translated that skill into the art of [00:11:35]engraving political cartoons. &lt;pe&gt;Dr. Joseph Warren&lt;/pe&gt; could climb up into a pulpit and [00:11:40]deliver an eloquent speech. &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; could do the same thing from his engravings [00:11:45]and these very graphic and very vivid and sometimes highly inflammatory political cartoons.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:11:50]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:11:55]In &lt;da&gt;1770&lt;/da&gt;, an altercation [00:12:00]between British soldiers and angry Bostonians resulted in death and injury of [00:12:05]several civilians. Thanks to patriot propaganda, including a hot-[00:12:10]selling print by &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, this event became one of the flash points of the [00:12:15]impending revolution, known throughout the world as the Boston Massacre.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:12:20]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; work as an engraver was very much [00:12:25]propaganda. I would add he was not the greatest artist in the world. In fact, the Boston [00:12:30]Massacre engraving, which is probably as best known, was not an original work. He, shall we say, [00:12:35]borrowed it from an artist named &lt;pe&gt;Pelham&lt;/pe&gt;, who was not too thrilled about it.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;HARRY PELHAM&lt;/sp&gt; [00:12:40]Sir, when I heard that you was cutting a plate of the late Murder, as I knew you [00:12:45]was not capable of doing it unless you copied it from mine, I leave you to [00:12:50]reflect upon and consider one of the most dishonorable actions you could [00:12:55]ever be guilty of, &lt;pe&gt;Pelham&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:13:00]This is pretty typical of how &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; did his political cartoons. It turns out [00:13:05]most engravers in those days copied from each other quite freely without attribution. You can generally find [00:13:10]art originals that &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; copied for all of his famous political prints right up to the Revolutionary [00:13:15]War.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; By [00:13:20]&lt;da&gt;1770&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; moved his wife and children into a three-story house in North Square &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, [00:13:25]but its solid walls were not enough to keep misfortune out. In [00:13:30]&lt;da&gt;May of 1773&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Sarah Revere&lt;/pe&gt; died shortly after bearing her [00:13:35]eighth child, daughter, &lt;pe&gt;Isannah&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; There are no portraits [00:13:40]of &lt;pe&gt;Sarah&lt;/pe&gt;, ah, we don't have a clear picture of her. Towards the end of their marriage, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was heavily [00:13:45]involved in the "Sons of Liberty." So I think certainly a lot of the burden of caring for the family fell [00:13:50]to her. And in fact, if not for her, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; could not have left so often [00:13:55]on, on all of his activities.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; By summer's [00:14:00]end, &lt;pe&gt;Isannah Revere&lt;/pe&gt; would join her mother in &lt;pl&gt;Boston's&lt;/pl&gt; Old Granary Burial [00:14:05]Ground. She was one of five &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; children who would not survive to [00:14:10]adulthood.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/sp&gt; Sometimes we think today, "Well, this [00:14:15]was such a relatively common occurrence on those days that either people a) didn't care too much, or b) they [00:14:20]steel themselves not to care." I don't think that's true. I think &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; did take the loss seriously.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:14:25]Now, a widower [00:14:30]with a young family to raise alone, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, silversmith, was about to be [00:14:35]drawn even farther into the explosive events leading to the American Revolution.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:14:40]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:14:50]In late summer of &lt;da&gt;1773&lt;/da&gt;, according to family legend, &lt;pe&gt;Paul [00:14:55]Revere&lt;/pe&gt; noticed an attractive young woman near a shop in the North End. By the fall of that [00:15:00]year, he would make her his wife. Her name was &lt;pe&gt;Rachel Walker&lt;/pe&gt; [00:15:05]and she was the love of &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; life.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/pe&gt; Coordinator of Research Paul Revere House&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/sp&gt; She's a very [00:15:10]warm person, and we can tell very capable. On the back of a receipt, ah, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; did ah, composed a proposal, [00:15:15]essentially a love letter to, ah, &lt;pe&gt;Rachel&lt;/pe&gt;, which is, is interesting because, uhm, [00:15:20]since we have so few personal letters from him about anything, it's just really nice to get [00:15:25]a window into his feelings for her, which were apparently very deep and, ah, very genuine.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;PAUL REVERE&lt;/sp&gt; [00:15:30]Added together with great care and Art will point out the Fair One [00:15:35]nearest my heart.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/sp&gt; And &lt;pe&gt;Rachel&lt;/pe&gt; inherited five or six children [00:15:40]plus a household and then soon after that, her husband was gone a lot on messenger riding and, and attending [00:15:45]political meetings. So she really inherited quite a bit of responsibility.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:15:50]Shortly after his second wedding, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; own [00:15:55]responsibilities in the revolutionary underground had also increased.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;&lt;/sp&gt; [00:16:00]Friends! Brethren! Countrymen! [00:16:05]That worst of plagues, the detested tea shipped for this Port by the East India Company, [00:16:10]is now arrived in the harbor; the hour of destruction, of manly opposition to [00:16:15]tyranny stares you in the face.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; &lt;da&gt;November 29, [00:16:20]1773&lt;/da&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:16:25]In the fall of &lt;da&gt;1773&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; patriots [00:16:30]were in an uproar. &lt;pl&gt;Britain&lt;/pl&gt; had repealed the so called "Townshend Acts," [00:16:35]taxes colonists had protested, but had left one duty intact: a tax [00:16:40]on tea. Now, a full-fledged Son of Liberty and member of [00:16:45]several underground societies, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was among those resolved to [00:16:50]resist.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/pe&gt; Professor of History Boston College&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; Bostonians resolved that the tea should not be landed, [00:16:55]that it should not be distributed, that it should not be consumed. [00:17:00]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; cartoons showing the British government forcing tea down [00:17:05]Americans' throats had certainly had an impact on the population. Bostonians [00:17:10]who might not wade through a political pamphlet would look [00:17:15]at one of &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; cartoons, get the political lesson immediately and be prepared [00:17:20]to act in opposition to the tea act or any other British regulation.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:17:25]While revolutionary [00:17:30]leaders tried unsuccessfully to persuade Boston merchants to refuse the tea, [00:17:35]secret committees like &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; own North Caucus Club rendezvous in [00:17:40] taverns, planning one of history's most brilliant acts of political theater.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:17:45]At a mass meeting at the old south meeting house, &lt;pe&gt;Sam Adams&lt;/pe&gt;, [00:17:50]who had been negotiating with the merchants, came to announce there is nothing else we can [00:17:55]do to save our country. And as if that were a signal, a war whoop [00:18:00]went up outside the meeting house and two bands of thinly-disguised [00:18:05]Indians, Bostonians, went down to the wharf, onto the ship [00:18:10]and unloaded its tea and dumped it in the harbor. [00:18:15]We don't know if &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; [00:18:20]actually was among that group of thinly-disguised Indians. Names were [00:18:25]secret, but it seems like he was a man who had contacts [00:18:30]among the group of people who would likely know their way around ships. [00:18:35]He was a leader; either he was there or he certainly knew what was going [00:18:40]to happen.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/sp&gt; Parliament was furious with the colonies for having destroyed [00:18:45]so much British East, East India Company Tea, which was essentially government tea in those days, and they [00:18:50]were gonna make an example out of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;. So they passed what are called the "Intolerable Acts." The most important probably [00:18:55]was shutting the port of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; and essentially that dried up the business in &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;. It was an extreme economic [00:19:00]threat. And looking at it now, you could only see that it had to provoke reaction. [00:19:05]It couldn't possibly have done otherwise.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:19:10]The closing of the port of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; deeply hurt &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; silversmithing [00:19:15]business. Once again, economic need thrust him even deeper into the [00:19:20]revolutionary effort. To earn extra money, he became a paid messenger rider for the [00:19:25]Committee of Safety.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Jayne E. Triber Ph.D&lt;/pe&gt; Revere Biographer&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; first [00:19:30]ride was on &lt;da&gt;December 17th, 1773&lt;/da&gt; when he carried news of the Boston Tea [00:19:35]Party to &lt;pl&gt;New York&lt;/pl&gt;. That was the beginning of his celebrated career as messenger of the [00:19:40]revolution. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was a vital link between the Boston Committee of Correspondence [00:19:45]and the Continental Congress in &lt;pl&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/pl&gt;. He would be asked to give his assessment, "What's going on in [00:19:50]&lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, and are there people, uh, supporting the protest?" Likewise, when he got back to &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, he [00:19:55]would be asked, "What's going on in &lt;pl&gt;New York&lt;/pl&gt; and &lt;pl&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/pl&gt;?" Uh, "What did they think about the Boston Tea Party? [00:20:00]Will we have support?" He went on from there to be not just a messenger, but somebody [00:20:05]who was involved in an intelligence network.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Narrator&lt;/sp&gt; [00:20:10]By &lt;da&gt;1774&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; had organized his own spy ring of [00:20:15]mechanics and artisans, working-class men from his North End neighborhood, and spent [00:20:20]long nights tracking the movements of the British Army stationed in &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;PAUL REVERE&lt;/sp&gt; [00:20:25]We held our meetings in the Green Dragon Tavern. [00:20:30]We were so careful that our meetings should be kept secret, that every time we met [00:20:35]every person swore upon the Bible. We frequently took turns, [00:20:40]two and two, to watch the soldiers by patrolling the streets all night. [00:20:45]&lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; Think about that. He works [00:20:50]all day and patrols the streets all night. So I think it says all about his [00:20:55]idealism, his belief that, "Hey, I have to sacrifice my sleep and, and my business [00:21:00]to serve a larger cause." I think, he very much thought that he was part of a potentially worldwide [00:21:05]movement to spread liberty. I think it also has a certain cloak and dagger aspect which he [00:21:10]must have found kind of appealing. Slowly, we see [00:21:15]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; assuming more and more responsibility in the revolutionary organization. At the [00:21:20]same time, he was often reminded that he lived in a deferential and heirarchal [00:21:25]society, that he was not the equal, of let's say &lt;pe&gt;James Otis&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;John Adams&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leechey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:21:30]To some degree, he wasn't really in the inner circle. He couldn't be because he was not [00:21:35]in the, of the upper class. But at the same time, sometimes I think he kinda held himself a little outside [00:21:40]on purpose. Maybe he felt that it made his own activities a little more the effective that way.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:21:45]Throughout &lt;da&gt;1774&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; activities [00:21:50]as courier and spy help spread the spirit of rebellion throughout &lt;pl&gt;New England&lt;/pl&gt;. [00:21:55]But the peak of his revolutionary career would come in the spring of [00:22:00]&lt;da&gt;1775&lt;/da&gt; with his midnight ride.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:22:05]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:22:10]Under cover of night on [00:22:15]&lt;da&gt;April 18th 1775&lt;/da&gt;, British troops set out from &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; toward [00:22:20]the outlying towns of &lt;pl&gt;Lexington&lt;/pl&gt; and &lt;pl&gt;Concord&lt;/pl&gt;. Their mission was to destroy [00:22:25]a large quantity of ammunitions stored there, a bold show of force intended to [00:22:30]thwart the rebellious colonists and their resistance to British rule. In reality, [00:22:35]&lt;pe&gt;Longfellow's&lt;/pe&gt; lone hero, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, was but one of the network of patriot [00:22:40]intelligence operators set out to foil this plan.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Jayne E. Triber Ph.D&lt;/pe&gt;/Revere Biographer&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:22:45]I think people think of the midnight ride as this very impetuous and madcap impromptu sort of [00:22:50]thing, uhm, where &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; leaps out of bed in the middle of the night, jumps on his horse and races through the [00:22:55]streets, when in fact, this was a carefully planned and carefully executed intelligence assignment.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/sp&gt; [00:23:00]The Saturday night preceding the 19th [00:23:05]of April, about 12 o'clock at night, the boats belonging to the [00:23:10]transports were all launched and carried under the sterns of the men-of-war. From these [00:23:15]movements, we expected something serious was to be transacted. &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:23:20]What they suspected was the British were actually either planning [00:23:25]to go to &lt;pl&gt;Lexington&lt;/pl&gt; to arrest &lt;pe&gt;John Hancock&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/pe&gt; or to the nearby town of [00:23:30]&lt;pl&gt;Concord&lt;/pl&gt; to destroy the colony's stores of gunpowder.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/pe&gt; Coordinator of Research Paul Revere House&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; met with [00:23:35]the Sons of Liberty in &lt;pl&gt;Charlestown&lt;/pl&gt;, which is right across the river from &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, and arranged that as soon as [00:23:40]soon as something would happen he was gonna have somebody show some signals from the top of the Old North [00:23:45]Church.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Longfellow&lt;/pe&gt; got it a little backward. The signals were not to &lt;pe&gt;Paul [00:23:50]Revere&lt;/pe&gt;. They were from him. The reason was what if &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; never got out of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;? What if [00:23:55]he was stopped as he rowed across the Charles, which was highly likely. So &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; came up with this very [00:24:00]ah, good plan, one of by land and two of by sea. That part is correct.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/sp&gt; [00:24:05]On Tuesday evening [00:24:10]the 18th, it was observed that a number of soldiers were marching toward the Common. 00:24:15]&lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:24:20]When, the actual evening that his midnight ride occurred, a messenger came to get him [00:24:25]and told him to go over the &lt;pe&gt;Dr. Joseph Warren's&lt;/pe&gt; house. And when he got there, he discovered that &lt;pe&gt;William Dawes&lt;/pe&gt;, [00:24:30]the other messenger rider that night, and sometimes forgotten about, had been sent by the land route. Revere was [00:24:35]given the same message that Dawes was to deliver to &lt;pe&gt;Adams&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Hancock&lt;/pe&gt; to, ah, say that the troops [00:24:40]were marching and that they were probably marching out into the countryside to arrest him.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:24:45]While &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; friend, [00:24:50]&lt;pe&gt;Robert Newman&lt;/pe&gt;, climbed to the top of the Old North Church steeple to hang the lantern signals, [00:24:55]two more patriots quietly rowed &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; across the river toward &lt;pl&gt;Charlestown&lt;/pl&gt;, [00:25:00]passing right under the bow of the British warship Somerset.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/sp&gt; [00:25:05]It was then young flood. The [00:25:10]ship was winding and the moon was rising. They landed me on &lt;pl&gt;Charlestown&lt;/pl&gt; side. [00:25:15]When I got into town, I met &lt;pe&gt;Colonel Conant&lt;/pe&gt; and several others. They said they had [00:25:20]seen our signals. I told them what was acting and I went to get me a horse."&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:25:25]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/sp&gt; [00:25:30]The moon shone bright. I had got almost over &lt;pl&gt;Charlestown&lt;/pl&gt; [00:25:35]Common towards &lt;pl&gt;Cambridge&lt;/pl&gt; when I saw two officers on horseback under the shade of a tree. [00:25:40]I turned my horse very quick and pushed for the &lt;pl&gt;Medford&lt;/pl&gt; Road.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:25:45]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; escape [00:25:50]took him on a detour through &lt;pl&gt;Medford&lt;/pl&gt; where he alerted the town militia. As [00:25:55]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; message spread, many more riders set off on their own midnight [00:26:00]rides.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/pe&gt; Professor of History Boston College&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; The myth is that &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; [00:26:05]acted alone, that he was a single, solitary, lone rider [00:26:10]taking the responsibility for alerting the whole countryside on his shoulders [00:26:15]alone. He had lots and lots of help on his ride. He and [00:26:20] dozens of others who were brought into motion by &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; ride [00:26:25]did alert the countryside.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;&lt;/sp&gt; [00:26:30]After that, I alarmed almost every house [00:26:35]until I got to &lt;pl&gt;Lexington&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; He did not [00:26:40]go racing through the countryside yelling, "The British are coming! The British are coming!" Number one, because if he would have done that, his horse [00:26:45]would be dropped dead after about 3 miles. The other thing is that he wouldn't have said, "The British are coming! The British are coming!" because [00:26:50]he was British, so was &lt;pe&gt;George Washington&lt;/pe&gt;, so was &lt;pe&gt;John Hancock&lt;/pe&gt;. I mean they thought of himself as [00:26:55]American-British. These were English, English subjects. And so, saying, "The British are coming," [00:27:00]I mean, if somebody would have heard that, they would have said, "What?"&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; The closest dialogue to [00:27:05]"The British are coming," occurs in &lt;pl&gt;Lexington&lt;/pl&gt;. He got to the parsonage of &lt;pe&gt;Reverend Jonas Clark&lt;/pe&gt; where [00:27:10]&lt;pe&gt;John Hancock&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/pe&gt; are staying. Ah, &lt;pe&gt;Sergeant William Munroe of &lt;/pe&gt; the Lexington Militia was [00:27:15]guarding the house. He said to &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, "The family has retired and they don't wish to be disturbed," [00:27:20]to which ah, a somewhat annoyed &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; said, "Noise? You'll have noise enough before long. [00:27:25]The regulars are coming out". About half hour later &lt;pe&gt;William Dawes&lt;/pe&gt; arrived. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; [00:27:30]said, "We refreshed ourselves." A mug of rum, whatever. He doesn't say. [00:27:35]Together they decided it might not be a bad idea to continue on to &lt;pl&gt;Concord&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:27:40]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; and [00:27:45]&lt;pe&gt;Dawes&lt;/pe&gt; set off for &lt;pl&gt;Concord&lt;/pl&gt;, meeting another patriot &lt;pe&gt;, Dr. Samuel Prescott&lt;/pe&gt; along [00:27:50]the way. The three men alarmed houses and farms all the way to &lt;pl&gt;Lincoln&lt;/pl&gt;, where they were [00:27:55]pursued by a patrol of British officers. &lt;pe&gt;Prescott&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Dawes&lt;/pe&gt; escaped, [00:28:00]but &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was taken prisoner.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/sp&gt; [00:28:05]One of them clapped his pistol to my head and told me he was going to ask some questions [00:28:10]and if I did not give true answers he would blow my brains out.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:28:15]When [00:28:20]the British officers learned who &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was, he said, they abused much. He was known to them [00:28:25]as a courier. He was quite well known and, ah, he immediately decided to [00:28:30]pull a fast one on them. He tells them, "I have alarmed the country all the way up. I should have [00:28:35]500 men there soon." Well of course the soldiers had no way of knowing that there were probably around [00:28:40]70-plus members of the Lexington Militia waiting at &lt;pl&gt;Lexington Green&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:28:45]Alarmed by this bluff, [00:28:50]the soldier's commandeered &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; horse and hurried back toward &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, [00:28:55]releasing him in sight of &lt;pl&gt;Lexington Green&lt;/pl&gt;. He arrived in time to hear the [00:29:00]opening shots of the American Revolution.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:29:05]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:29:10]You know the rest. In the books you have read how the British [00:29:15]regulars fired and fled, how the farmers gave them ball for [00:29:20]ball from behind each fence and farmyard wall.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:29:25]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;&lt;/sp&gt; [00:29:35]All eyes are turned upon the tragical event of the 19th. [00:29:40]We are unanimous in the resolution to die or be [00:29:45]free. A &lt;pl&gt;New England&lt;/pl&gt; patriot, &lt;da&gt;April 25th 1775&lt;/da&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:29:50]The shot [00:29:55]heard around the world had been fired. The Revolutionary War had begun. [00:30:00]Ordinary men like &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; had helped fellow patriots to prepare [00:30:05]for the possibility of war. And when the time came, helped make certain they were [00:30:10]ready. But once the fighting was underway, the dynamics of leadership [00:30:15]began to change.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Jayne E. Triber Ph.D&lt;/pe&gt;/Revere Biographer&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; In the &lt;da&gt;1770's&lt;/da&gt;, when [00:30:20]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was working as a courier, he's virtually at the center of history. Then he makes [00:30:25]his midnight ride. Clearly, another important role. I think the irony of the midnight [00:30:30]ride is that's really the height of &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; role in the revolution. [00:30:35]After the ride, people like &lt;pe&gt;John&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/pe&gt; moved on to the Continental Congress of [00:30:40]&lt;pl&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/pl&gt;. They're drafting a new government, they are creating a new society. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; pretty much [00:30:45]is relegated to a secondary role.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:30:50]During the siege of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; continued [00:30:55]to use his skills to aid the patriot cause. He managed to smuggle his printing press [00:31:00]out of the city and engraved copper plates to print currency. He helped procure [00:31:05]cannon and gun powder and participated in some military expeditions. But [00:31:10]because he was not a gentleman, his fellow revolutionaries did not consider [00:31:15]him officer material.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; He [00:31:20]very much wanted to be a Continental Army officer. And I think it was a very [00:31:25]bitter and a sad episode of his life. He said "I have never been taken notice of by [00:31:30]those I considered my friends. I shall have to be contented in the state service." He [00:31:35]ended up merely as a Colonel in a Massachusetts artillery regiment and the war years were not [00:31:40]glorious at all for &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/pe&gt; Coordinator of Research Paul Revere House&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt;For most of the three years he was in [00:31:45]the Massachusetts Army, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was the commander of &lt;pl&gt;Castle Island&lt;/pl&gt;, which was the port in &lt;pl&gt;Boston Harbor&lt;/pl&gt;. And [00:31:50]basically, his task was to stay on guard in case the English ever came back, which they never did. So [00:31:55]his command degenerated rather rapidly into keeping his men from deserting, [00:32:00]attempting to get them the supplies eventually, and holding innumerable court marshals for minor [00:32:05]offenses.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:32:10]Finally, in &lt;da&gt;July of 1779&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was appointed [00:32:15]artillery officer in a massive amphibious expedition to dislodge the British from [00:32:20] &lt;pl&gt;Penobscot Bay, Maine&lt;/pl&gt;. Ironically, the officer second in [00:32:25]command of the land troops was &lt;pe&gt;Brigadier General Peleg Wadsworth&lt;/pe&gt;, the grandfather [00:32:30]of &lt;pe&gt;Henry Wadsworth Longfellow&lt;/pe&gt;, the poet who would make &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; a legend.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:32:35]The Penobscot Expedition was &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; [00:32:40]only chance really to, to finally gain some sort of glory and reputation, not only in his [00:32:45]own attempt but perhaps for history. It turned out to be probably the greatest disaster of his life.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:32:50]It's the largest amphibious operation that any American army [00:32:55]was involved in prior to D-day. Forty-some ships, many of which were privateers, [00:33:00]at least a thousand and possibly as many as 1500 soldiers including some Indian [00:33:05]tribes; a lot of different authorities involved, the Massachusetts Army, the Continental Navy, the New Hampshire [00:33:10]Army, and various other authorities. They were sent to capture a rather small port. They really should have [00:33:15]been able to take the port rather easily, but apparently, there's a lot of bickering between the Navy and the Army.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/pe&gt; Professor of History Boston College&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:33:20]The Naval leaders were too timid. The British [00:33:25]then sent some ships up from &lt;pl&gt;New York&lt;/pl&gt;, caught the American Navy sitting in the [00:33:30]water. The American fleets, they attempted to flee, they ran their ships [00:33:35]aground. Sailors and soldiers had to jump off, save themselves [00:33:40]as best they could. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; wandered up and down the &lt;pl&gt;Penobscot&lt;/pl&gt; for the better [00:33:45]part of the day looking for his soldiers. It was a disaster.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:33:50]During the retreat, &lt;pe&gt;Reveres's&lt;/pe&gt; actions were somewhat questionable. [00:33:55]For one thing, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; ordered his men back to &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, although he technically did not have the authority. [00:34:00]But there's an even more striking episode. When &lt;pe&gt;General Wadsworth&lt;/pe&gt; asked &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; to [00:34:05]turn over his boat so they could evacuate the crew of the schooner that was drifting towards the enemy, [00:34:10]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; responded that &lt;pe&gt;General Wadsworth&lt;/pe&gt; have no right to command him. I think he [00:34:15]simply wasn't thinking, but it didn't look good at all.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:34:20]Once back in &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; and other [00:34:25]officers from the ill-fated expedition were charged with insubordination [00:34:30]and cowardice.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; Revere could have let [00:34:35]whole issue of his censure go if he wanted to. It really didn't affect his business. [00:34:40]I think the problem was he felt his honor had been besmirched, and this was very important. And so [00:34:45]he wanted to set the record straight. He applied seven times for a court-martial and eventually did get a court-martial.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;&lt;/sp&gt; [00:34:50]The court finds that the whole army was in [00:34:55]such great confusion and so scattered and dispersed, that no regular [00:35:00]orders would or could be given and that &lt;pe&gt;Lieutenant-Colonel Paul [00:35:05]Revere&lt;/pe&gt; be acquitted with equal honor of the other officers of the same expedition. [00:35:10]Court-martial decision, &lt;da&gt;1782&lt;/da&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:35:15]I think Penobscot shook him to his core. Ironically, though, [00:35:20]he emerged I think after time with more confidence in the future. And [00:35:25]in the &lt;da&gt;1780s&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; established a reputation not as a military officer but [00:35:30]as a public-spirited citizen and a successful merchant and manufacturer.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;[00:35:35]&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; In [00:35:40]&lt;da&gt;1785&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;Great Britain&lt;/pl&gt; signed the Treaty of Paris, officially acknowledging [00:35:45]&lt;pl&gt;America's&lt;/pl&gt; independence, but the &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; to which &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; returned [00:35:50]after the war was in desperate need of rebuilding.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:35:55]The war, particularly for &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, [00:36:00]was devastating. The city had stagnated, &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; [00:36:05]business was in shambles, tastes had changed. [00:36:10]So the one thing the revolution did do was create [00:36:15]a, a market for silver for the ordinary [00:36:20]folk, rather than a few carefully wrought pieces for the well-to-[00:36:25]do. &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; recognized this and changed the way he did [00:36:30]business, began to manufacture more items for mass consumption, [00:36:35]and that worked. He got on his feet again. His [00:36:40]business took off again and he went into other businesses.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:36:45]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; expanded the silversmith shop into a hardware store in [00:36:50]&lt;da&gt;1783&lt;/da&gt;. In &lt;da&gt;1788&lt;/da&gt;, he opened a foundry in &lt;pl&gt;Boston's&lt;/pl&gt; North End. He made [00:36:55]nails and window weights, and stoves, and firebacks. And then in the &lt;da&gt;1790s&lt;/da&gt;, [00:37:00]he started producing cannon and ordnance. He became a nationally recognized authority [00:37:05]on cannon.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; Then he took up a new business[00:37:10], making bells. That was a smart move. [00:37:15]There was a religious revival after the revolution, and more churches [00:37:20]meant a need for more church bells. [00:37:25]In &lt;da&gt;1800&lt;/da&gt;, when &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; was nearly 65 years [00:37:30]old with $25,000 of his, of his own money, [00:37:35]he began yet another new business: the rolling of copper. It is [00:37:40]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; copper sheeting that's used to line the bottom of the U.S.S. Constitution. [00:37:45]It is &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; copper sheeting that covers the dome [00:37:50]in the new state house. It is [00:37:55]&lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; copper sheeting that lines the bottoms of dozens of merchant ships [00:38:00]throughout the commonwealth. It turns out to be [00:38:05]a very prosperous business.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; What he ended up [00:38:10]becoming was essentially one of &lt;pl&gt;America's&lt;/pl&gt; earliest industrialists. I don't think he really thought of himself that way. I think he thought of [00:38:15]himself still as a craftsman. And the foundry and copper mill business did make him fairly wealthy by the end of his life.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:38:20]But &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; [00:38:25]postwar years were not only filled with economic achievements. Having learned well [00:38:30]the puritan lessons of the importance of community service, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; went on to become one [00:38:35]of &lt;pl&gt;Massachusetts'&lt;/pl&gt; most productive citizens.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; [00:38:40]Sometimes it's been noted that &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; didn't run for political office but actually in a way, he did have a rather [00:38:45]full political career, if you define it slightly differently. He was involved in many voluntary organizations, [00:38:50]and particularly the freemasons. He was Grand Master of Massachusetts Grand Lodge for three years. [00:38:55]He was in the early library society. He's one of the founders of the Charitable Mechanics Association.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Alan Rogers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:39:00]When the constitution, the draft of the [00:39:05]constitution of &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; was sent to the States for ratification, [00:39:10]everyone looked to &lt;pl&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/pl&gt;. When the contest was in doubt, &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; [00:39:15]called a meeting of the mechanics, the working men of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; in the Green [00:39:20]Dragon Tavern. Hundreds of artisans gathered to [00:39:25]hear &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; and others make an argument for ratification of the constitution. [00:39:30]That mechanics meeting, the resolution passed by the mechanics in [00:39:35]favor of the constitution, did in fact persuade &lt;pe&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/pe&gt; [00:39:40]that he too should be for ratification of the constitution. [00:39:45]So too then was &lt;pe&gt;John Hancock&lt;/pe&gt;. So those key [00:39:50]players in this political contest were persuaded by the action that [00:39:55]&lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; took.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:40:00]By &lt;da&gt;1811&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, [00:40:05]goldsmith had become a wealthy man. He and &lt;pe&gt;Rachel&lt;/pe&gt; spent long lazy [00:40:10]days at their country home in &lt;pl&gt;Canton Dale&lt;/pl&gt;, enjoying the fruits of their many [00:40:15]years of labor.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/sp&gt; "Not [00:40:20]distant far from Taunton road, in &lt;pl&gt;Canton Dale&lt;/pl&gt; is my abode. [00:40:25]My cot, though small, my mind's at ease. My Better Half [00:40:30]takes pains to please. Content sits lolling in a chair, [00:40:35]and all my friends find welcome there. In my last stage, how [00:40:40]blessed am I, defined content and plenty by." [00:40:45]&lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;da&gt;1811&lt;/da&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Patrick Leehey&lt;/sp&gt; By the end of his life, [00:40:50]I would say &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; had pretty much risen into the ranks of gentlemen. And &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; [00:40:55]youngest son &lt;pe&gt;John&lt;/pe&gt;, went to Harvard, which is a college, and eventually became a doctor. So [00:41:00]in a sense, almost by through his, through his youngest son, the family moved up into [00:41:05]the upper class.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:41:10]Died in this town on Saturday after a short [00:41:15]but distressing illness, &lt;pe&gt;Mrs. Rachel&lt;/pe&gt;, wife of &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; Esq. [00:41:20]Age 68. Boston Chronicle [00:41:25]&lt;da&gt;July 1st 1813&lt;/da&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:41:30]I think she really was, really quite a remarkable woman. Her death must have been quite a blow to &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt;. [00:41:35]Her death was also a kind of a double blow because a few months [00:41:40]previously, his oldest son had died as well. So I think his later years were marred by, by these [00:41:45]two losses, also marred I think by &lt;pe&gt;Revere's&lt;/pe&gt; disapproval of a lot of what was [00:41:50]going on in American society. He didn't approve of the political changes. He was a staunch Federalist. [00:41:55]He believed in social order and harmony and deference, and he saw the &lt;pe&gt;Jeffersons&lt;/pe&gt; as [00:42:00]underming all of that with their belief in equality. He kept a very close [00:42:05]watch on the world around him from his retirement, wanting not just to sit there quietly and observe, [00:42:10]but really be up in events and be part of things. I think it's nice that he kept that up to the end.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:42:15][Sil.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:20]On Sunday, &lt;da&gt;May 10th 1818&lt;/da&gt;, the [00:42:25]church bells of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, including those cast by &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; himself, tolled [00:42:30]a death knell. &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, one of the city's most honored citizens, [00:42:35]had died at the age of 83.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:40]I think he would have absolutely loved the notoriety that came to him because of Longfellow's poem. [00:42:45]At the same time, I think he might also have liked a much more simpler description of his life. [00:42:50]It was delivered by a man who knew him, &lt;pe&gt;William Theodore&lt;/pe&gt;. &lt;pe&gt;Theodore&lt;/pe&gt; had been one of &lt;pe&gt;John [00:42:55]Adams's&lt;/pe&gt; law clerks. And he said of &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt; quite simply, "&lt;pe&gt;Mr. Revere&lt;/pe&gt; throughout [00:43:00]life was an upright, useful, respectable citizen." That, in fact, should have been the [00:43:05]goal of anybody, who had committed himself to this patriot cause to be an [00:43:10]upright useful citizen. You can't ask for anything more.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;NARRATOR&lt;/sp&gt; [00:43:15]For, borne on the night-wind of the past, [00:43:20]through all our history to the last, in the hour of darkness [00:43:25]and peril and need, the people will waken and listen to [00:43:30]hear the hurrying hoof-beats of that steed, and the [00:43:35]midnight message of &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:43:40][Sil.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:43:45]Throughout history, ordinary men and women routinely perform acts [00:43:50]of everyday heroism, acts that often go forgotten. [00:43:55]Thanks to &lt;pe&gt;Longfellow's&lt;/pe&gt; poem, one such hero will always live in our [00:44:00]imaginations, a Boston silversmith named &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;Craig Haffner&lt;/pe&gt; &amp; &lt;pe&gt;Donna E. Lusitana&lt;/pe&gt; Produced by &lt;pe&gt;Melissa Jo Peltier&lt;/pe&gt; Series Producer &lt;pe&gt;Melanie Blythe&lt;/pe&gt; Series Producer &lt;pe&gt;Deborah M. Davis&lt;/pe&gt; Music by &lt;pe&gt;Christopher L. Stone&lt;/pe&gt; Editor &lt;pe&gt;Steve Pomerantz&lt;/pe&gt; Post Production Coordinator &lt;pe&gt;Eric Lindstrom&lt;/pe&gt; Production Coordinator &lt;pe&gt;Louis Tarantino&lt;/pe&gt; Post Production Assistant &lt;pe&gt;Rob Senkel&lt;/pe&gt; Production Assistant &lt;pe&gt;Lynn Borzumato&lt;/pe&gt; Graphic Artist &lt;pe&gt;Melinda Lawton&lt;/pe&gt; Director of Photography &lt;pe&gt;Dave Pryke&lt;/pe&gt; Field Engineers &lt;pe&gt;Ken Fraser&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;James Fitzgerald&lt;/pe&gt; Grip &lt;pe&gt;Geoff Rockwell&lt;/pe&gt; Composite Editor &lt;pe&gt;Terence Curren&lt;/pe&gt; Electronic Graphics &lt;pe&gt;Leigh Thomas&lt;/pe&gt; Post Production Services Provided by Matchframe Video Animatics By Zona Productions &lt;pe&gt;Timothy Kitz&lt;/pe&gt; Archival Sources The Paul Revere Memorial Association/The Paul Revere House Massachusetts Historical Society The Bostonian Society/Old State House History Museum Courtesy, Winterthur Museum Independence National Historical Park Museum of Fine Arts, &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt; Library of Congress Courtesy, American Antiquarian Society Old North Church &lt;pl&gt;Boston, Massachusetts&lt;/pl&gt; North Wind Picture Archives Maine Historical Society Boston Athenaeum Grand Lodge of Masons in &lt;pl&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/pl&gt; Courtesy, U.S. Naval Academy National Archives &lt;pl&gt;Washington, D.C&lt;/pl&gt;. Courtesy of the Trustees of The Boston Public Library Special Thanks To: The Paul Revere Memorial Association/The Paul Revere House Strawberry Banke Museum &lt;pl&gt;Portsmouth, New Hampshire&lt;/pl&gt; Old North Church &lt;pl&gt;Boston, Massachusetts&lt;/pl&gt; Old South Meeting House &lt;pe&gt;Lisa Bourgoujian&lt;/pe&gt; 10th Massachusetts Tallmadge's Troops 2nd Continental Dragoons The Rhode Island Regiment H.M. 10th Regiment of Foot 2nd Massachusetts Regiments Post Production Supervisor for A&amp;E &lt;pe&gt;Diane Ferenczi&lt;/pe&gt; A&amp;E Manager Documentary Programming &lt;pe&gt;Bill Harris&lt;/pe&gt; A&amp;E Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;Michael Cascio&lt;/pe&gt; Executive in Charge of Production &lt;pe&gt;Steven Lewis&lt;/pe&gt; Produced by Greystone Communications, Inc. for A&amp;E Network &lt;pe&gt;PAUL REVERE&lt;/pe&gt;: The Midnight Rider (c) &lt;da&gt;1995&lt;/da&gt; A&amp;E Television Networks All Rights Reserved GREYSTONE A&amp;E Home Video (c) &lt;da&gt;2004&lt;/da&gt; A&amp;E Television Networks. All Rights Reserved.&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;END TRANSCRIPT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jack Perkins&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:20]On Sunday, &lt;da&gt;May 10th 1818&lt;/da&gt;, the [00:42:25]church bells of &lt;pl&gt;Boston&lt;/pl&gt;, including those cast by &lt;pe&gt;Revere&lt;/pe&gt; himself, tolled [00:42:30]a death knell. &lt;pe&gt;Paul Revere&lt;/pe&gt;, one of the city's most honored citizens, [00:42:35]had died at the age of 83.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Jayne E. Triber&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:40]I think he would have absolutely loved the notoriety that came to him because of Longfellow's poem. [00:42:45]At the same time, I think he might also have liked a much more simpler description of his life. [00:42:50]It was delivered by a man who knew him, &lt;pe&gt;William Theodore&lt;/pe&gt;. &lt;pe&gt;Theodore&lt;/pe&gt; had been one of &lt;pe&gt;John [00:42:55]Adams's&lt;/pe&gt; law clerks. And </field>
      <field name="copyright_message">Copyright 2008 A&amp;E Television Networks</field>
      <field name="countryfilter">US CA AR BS BZ BM BO BR CL CO CR DO EC GT HN JM MX NI PY PE PR LC MF TT UY VE AF AM AU AZ BH BN MM CN CK FJ GE GU HK IN ID IR IQ IL PS JP JO KZ KW KG LB MO MY MV FM MN NP NZ KP OM PK PG PH QA RU SA SG KR LK TW TJ TH TL TR TM AE VU VN YE DZ BW TD DJ EG ET GM GH KE LR MW MU MA NG SN SC ZA SZ UG ZM ZW AL AT BY BE BA BG HR CY CZ DK EE FI FR DE GR HU IS IE IT LV LI LT LU MK MT MD MC ME NL NO PL PT RO RS SK SI ES SE CH UA GB UZ</field>
      <field name="ctiv_associated_materials">0</field>
      <field name="digital_publication_date">2011-10-03</field>
      <field name="digital_publication_date_facet">2011-10-03T12:52:11Z</field>
      <field name="digital_publisher">Alexander Street Press</field>
      <field name="digital_publisher_place">Alexandria, VA</field>
      <field name="discipline_subject_hierarchy">History|American History|Colonial Era (1650-1765)</field>
      <field name="discipline_subject_hierarchy">American Studies|American History|Colonial Era (1650-1765)</field>
      <field name="discipline_subject_hierarchy">History|American History|Revolutionary Era (1765-1789)</field>
      <field name="discipline_subject_hierarchy">American Studies|American History|Revolutionary Era (1765-1789)</field>
      <field name="discipline_tertiary_subject_hierarchy">History|American History|Colonial Era (1650-1765)</field>
      <field name="discipline_tertiary_subject_hierarchy">American Studies|American History|Colonial Era (1650-1765)</field>
      <field name="discipline_tertiary_subject_hierarchy">History|American History|Revolutionary Era (1765-1789)</field>
      <field name="discipline_tertiary_subject_hierarchy">American Studies|American History|Revolutionary Era (1765-1789)</field>
      <field name="display_order">0</field>
      <field name="document_type">Documentary</field>
      <field name="dorp_id">1000993020</field>
      <field name="downloadable">0</field>
      <field name="duration">2711</field>
      <field name="eba_price">131.78</field>
      <field name="exclude_from_release">0</field>
      <field name="format">Video</field>
      <field name="google_exposure">true</field>
      <field name="group_id">1785530</field>
      <field name="group_real_title">paul revere the midnight rider</field>
      <field name="groupfilter">history</field>
      <field name="groupfilter">american-studies</field>
      <field name="grouping_path">Paul Revere: The Midnight Rider</field>
      <field name="historical_event">Paul Revere's Ride, MA, April 18, 1775</field>
      <field name="historical_event_hierarchy">11775090317830903*American Revolution, 1775-1783|11775041817750418*Paul Revere's Ride, MA, April 18, 1775</field>
      <field name="history_era">Early National Era (17901828)</field>
      <field name="history_era">Revolutionary Era (17651789)</field>
      <field name="history_era_facet">3790*Early National Era (17901828)</field>
      <field name="history_era_facet">3765*Revolutionary Era (17651789)</field>
      <field name="inbound_link_id">446938</field>
      <field name="join_id">person|774995</field>
      <field name="join_id">person|769137</field>
      <field name="join_id">organization|32731</field>
      <field name="language_of_edition">English</field>
      <field name="marc_id">ASP1000993020/ahiv</field>
      <field name="marc_id">ASP1000993020/vast</field>
      <field name="object_id">bibliographic_entity|video_work|1785530</field>
      <field name="object_subtype">video_work</field>
      <field name="object_type">bibliographic_entity</field>
      <field name="organization_role_facet">ae television networks*A&amp;E Television Networks|32731</field>
      <field name="organization_role_facet">ae television networks*A&amp;E Television Networks|32731|Publisher</field>
      <field name="original_language">English</field>
      <field name="person_discussed">Paul Revere</field>
      <field name="person_discussed_facet">revere paul*Revere, Paul|774995</field>
      <field name="person_discussed_select_term">Revere, Paul</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">revere paul*Revere, Paul|774995</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">revere paul*Revere, Paul|774995|Person Discussed</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">revere paul*Revere, Paul|774995|Works about</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">peltier melissa jo*Peltier, Melissa Jo|769137</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">peltier melissa jo*Peltier, Melissa Jo|769137|Producer</field>
      <field name="place_discussed">Boston, MA</field>
      <field name="place_subject_hierarchy">North and Central America|United States|Massachusetts|Boston, MA</field>
      <field name="processed_timestamp">2014-07-18T06:53:35Z</field>
      <field name="producer">Melissa Jo Peltier</field>
      <field name="producer_facet">peltier melissa jo*Peltier, Melissa Jo|769137</field>
      <field name="producer_select_term">Peltier, Melissa Jo</field>
      <field name="product_code">AHIV</field>
      <field name="product_code">HISC</field>
      <field name="product_code">VASS</field>
      <field name="publication_date">2005</field>
      <field name="publication_date_facet">2005</field>
      <field name="publication_date_sort">20059999</field>
      <field name="publication_place_hierarchy">North and Central America|United States|New York|New York, NY</field>
      <field name="publication_type">Monograph</field>
      <field name="publisher">A&amp;E Television Networks</field>
      <field name="publisher_facet">ae television networks*A&amp;E Television Networks|32731</field>
      <field name="publisher_place">New York, NY</field>
      <field name="publisher_select_term">A&amp;E Television Networks</field>
      <field name="real_title">Paul Revere: The Midnight Rider</field>
      <field name="real_title_sort">paul revere the midnight rider</field>
      <field name="release_date">2005</field>
      <field name="release_year_facet">2005</field>
      <field name="subcommunityfilter">colonial</field>
      <field name="subcommunityfilter">revolutionary</field>
      <field name="suppress_eba">0</field>
      <field name="territorial_restrictions_whitelist">229</field>
      <field name="thumbnail_id">1000993020</field>
      <field name="timecode">1000993020-1-00:00:00-00:45:11</field>
      <field name="unitaccess">AHIV-V1</field>
      <field name="unitaccess">VAST-BF</field>
      <field name="unitaccess">PVST-BF</field>
      <field name="unitaccess_collection">AHIV-V1|American History in Video</field>
      <field name="unitaccess_collection">VAST-BF|VAST: Academic Video Online</field>
      <field name="unitaccess_collection">PVST-BF|Public Library Video Online</field>
      <field name="video_series">Biography</field>
      <field name="video_thumbnail">180</field>
      <field name="works_about_facet">revere paul*Revere, Paul|774995</field>
      <field name="error_msg">'0000' date found for creation_date.</field>
      <field name="error_code">C0722</field>
      <field name="error_msg">Cardinality error: more than one value encountered for Lazr Sort Year: 2005,2005.</field>
   </doc>
   <doc>
      <field name="abstract">Explores the origins, conduct, military strategies and political implications of this pivotal Cold War struggle. Presents rare archival film footage, combined with interviews of American veterans of the Korean War.</field>
      <field name="asp_community">American History</field>
      <field name="asp_group">History</field>
      <field name="asp_group">American Studies</field>
      <field name="asp_oclc">677926384</field>
      <field name="asp_release_date">2011-10-03T12:52:11Z</field>
      <field name="asp_tertiary_community">Post-war Era (1945-1960)</field>
      <field name="bibliographic_summary">Video Work: Making of a Bloodbath</field>
      <field name="catalog_number">AAE-71093</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|455074</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|455079</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|455080</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|455081</field>
      <field name="child_id">bibliographic_entity|video_track|455102</field>
      <field name="communityfilter">american-history</field>
      <field name="content_en">&lt;asp id="d1000993009" author="" lang="English" lld="" isbn="" lccn="" fd="DORP" lp="Y"&gt;&lt;p&gt;TRANSCRIPT OF VIDEO FILE:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;______________________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;BEGIN TRANSCRIPT:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;FBI WARNING Federal law provides severe civil and criminal penalties for the unauthorized reproduction, distribution or exhibition of copyrighted of motion pictures, video tapes or video discs. Criminal copyright infringement is investigated by the FBI and may constitute a felony with a maximum penalty of up to five years in prison and/or a $250,000 fine.&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Reach across time [00:00:15]and see yourself. You stand tall against terrifying enemies. [00:00:20]You build masterpieces and break down [00:00:25]barriers. You rush into the future and meet your [00:00:30]past. For every time, at every moment, the official [00:00:35]network of every millennium. The History Channel. [00:00:40]Where the past comes alive.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:00:45]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;The Korean War: FIRE &amp; ICE&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:00:55]The broiling Asian summer of &lt;da&gt;1950&lt;/da&gt; had to be some sort of nightmare. [00:01:00]Barely five years after they had won brilliant [00:01:05]victories over huge well-armed enemies across two oceans, [00:01:10]Western armies, possessors of the atom bomb were being humiliated, slaughtered [00:01:15]and thrown backward. The rampaging enemy was not some formidable world [00:01:20]power. The humbling defeats were being inflicted by a peasant army, [00:01:25]representing less than half of an almost unknown nation. [00:01:30]Indeed, most people have to go to a remote corner of the world map to locate the [00:01:35]new battleground, &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;DONALD P. GREGG&lt;/pe&gt; FORMER AMBASSADOR TO &lt;pl&gt;KOREA&lt;/pl&gt;&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Donald P. Gregg&lt;/sp&gt; My aunt [00:01:40]came in and said, "&lt;pe&gt;Donald&lt;/pe&gt;, the war has started in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;." And I went to an atlas to find where [00:01:45]&lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; was. I couldn't find it.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; The communist [00:01:50]North Korean assault that rolled across the border of &lt;pl&gt;South Korea&lt;/pl&gt; on &lt;da&gt;June 25th, [00:01:55]1950&lt;/da&gt;, was an ambush that astounded not only the invaded state but a [00:02:00]Western world that had only begun to see its crucial interests in the far reaches of Asia.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:02:05]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:02:10]The Russian bear and the Chinese behemoth suddenly seemed deeply [00:02:15]implicated in new and naked military aggression. [00:02:20]The swaggering West had assumed that its military might advancing under [00:02:25]a pure United Nations flag would cross into &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; and quickly snuff out the [00:02:30]upstart attack.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:02:35]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; But in a few short weeks, the humbled UN forces found [00:02:40]themselves about to be hurled off the bloody &lt;pl&gt;Korean Peninsula&lt;/pl&gt; and into the sea. [00:02:45]Over a half million UN soldiers and [00:02:50]a million and a half Korean and Chinese were about to become casualties in the [00:02:55]following three bloody years of what was to be called "The Forgotten War."&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:03:00]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:03:05]But it has not been forgotten by anybody who fought there.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. ROBERT BLACK&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt; (RET.) AUTHOR: "RANGERS IN &lt;pl&gt;KOREA&lt;/pl&gt;"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Robert Black&lt;/sp&gt; [00:03:10]Some Korean War veterans believe that we lost the war, some [00:03:15]believe that we won the war and some believe that our men died for a tie. In truth, we did [00:03:20]all three.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:03:25]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Donald P. Gregg&lt;/sp&gt; But I think the Korean War is a war that we should have [00:03:30]fought, that we were right to have fought.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; The Korean tragedy had [00:03:35]origins in both mistakes and inevitabilities.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:03:40]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:03:55]The explosion would thrust an unknown nation into the white-hot center of world affairs [00:04:00]for three terrible years.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:04:05]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;MAKING OF A BLOODBATH&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:04:10]The peninsula nation thrusting south between the &lt;pl&gt;Yellow Sea&lt;/pl&gt; and the &lt;pl&gt;Sea of [00:04:15]Japan&lt;/pl&gt; is a land the size of &lt;pl&gt;Utah&lt;/pl&gt;. It stretches some [00:04:20]635 miles at its longest stretch and is 150 miles across at its [00:04:25]widest. The main islands of &lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt; lie just 120 miles [00:04:30]away. Its mountainous backbone, the &lt;pl&gt;Taebaek Mountains&lt;/pl&gt; has peaks above [00:04:35]8,000 feet. But &lt;pl&gt;Korea's&lt;/pl&gt; location gives it stature far beyond [00:04:40]its modest borders.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. ROD PASCHALL&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt; (RET.) AUTHOR: "&lt;pl&gt;KOREA&lt;/pl&gt;: WITNESS TO WAR"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Rod Paschall&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; is the tinderbox of Asia. [00:04:45]Ah, geographically, it draws in several major powers, [00:04:50]&lt;pl&gt;Russia&lt;/pl&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;China&lt;/pl&gt; and &lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt;. &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; sits right in the middle of that [00:04:55]and right in the middle of major American interests.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:05:00]&lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; reclaimed its liberty in &lt;da&gt;1945&lt;/da&gt;, after [00:05:05]many harsh years of Japanese rule, with the defeat of &lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt; in World War II. [00:05:10]The &lt;pl&gt;Soviet Union&lt;/pl&gt;, a last minute entrant into the [00:05:15]Pacific War, had obtained agreements to occupy the North, while the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; [00:05:20]occupied the South. The demarcation would become the 38th Parallel [00:05:25]which divided the country roughly in half. [00:05:30]The Cairo and Potsdam Conferences of the Allied powers of World War II [00:05:35]had agreed to make &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; free and independent. Easier agreed [00:05:40]to than done. For the next three years, as the Cold War between [00:05:45]East and West heated up, there were fruitless negotiations between Russians and [00:05:50]Americans to unify the country.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;LT. GEN. BERNARD E. TRAINOR&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC(RET.)&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Bernard E. Trainor&lt;/sp&gt; [00:05:55]They both left behind surrogate military. Both of them [00:06:00]led by people who wanted to see the Peninsula united, [00:06:05]as did the Korean people as a whole. But under whose tutelage?&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:06:10]With the nationwide election proposed by the UN boycotted by the North, [00:06:15]the South voted alone. The Republic of &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; was established in &lt;da&gt;August of [00:06:20]1948&lt;/da&gt;, with &lt;pe&gt;Attorney Syngman Rhee&lt;/pe&gt; as its president.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Donald P. Gregg&lt;/sp&gt; [00:06:25]He spoke English. He had, ah, been educated at Princeton. He was [00:06:30]known to Americans. Ah, he was very ambitious, he was very ruthless and I think he was sort of [00:06:35]the obvious figure on the entire landscape we had to deal with.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:06:40]In September, the North established the Democratic People's Republic with &lt;pe&gt;Kim Il-sung&lt;/pe&gt;, [00:06:45]a leader of the anti-Japanese resistance, as its premier.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Donald P. Gregg&lt;/sp&gt; [00:06:50]He had great charm, he had great ruthlessness and he was a [00:06:55]tremendously adroit politician. As a CIA officer, I was [00:07:00]working against &lt;pl&gt;North Korea&lt;/pl&gt; for years and it was very interesting for us to [00:07:05]watch him balance his Soviet and Chinese allies. He would never get sucked [00:07:10]irretrievably into the orbit of either one.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:07:15]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Building on the desire of all the Korean people for a [00:07:20]unified nation, both &lt;pe&gt;Rhee&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Kim Il-sung&lt;/pe&gt; were dangerously, vocally [00:07:25]belligerent and likely to attack one another in a war for total conquest of the peninsula. [00:07:30]To a miscalculating &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt;, &lt;pe&gt;Rhee&lt;/pe&gt; seemed [00:07:35]most likely to launch hostility and upset the hard won balance of power in the Far East. [00:07:40]And the Americans proceeded to make a vast mistake.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;BEVIN ALEXANDER&lt;/pe&gt; AUTHOR :"&lt;pl&gt;KOREA&lt;/pl&gt;-THE FIRST WAR WE LOST"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Bevin Alexander&lt;/sp&gt; [00:07:45]The &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; deliberately refused to give &lt;pl&gt;South [00:07:50]Korea&lt;/pl&gt; any weapons that would stop attack. And they did this because they were [00:07:55]afraid &lt;pe&gt;Syngman Rhee&lt;/pe&gt; would attack the North, if he had any weapons that could [00:08:00]do any real damage to the North. And for that reason, the South Korean Army [00:08:05]did not have any weapons whatsoever to stop the North Korean tank attack.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:08:10]The Soviets had no such compunctions. They supplied [00:08:15]&lt;pl&gt;North Korea&lt;/pl&gt; with an arsenal of 150 first-line tanks, of [00:08:20]which the South had none, and of heavy-caliber artillery pieces that hugely [00:08:25]outnumbered, outhit and outranged the South Korean guns. [00:08:30]And why not? &lt;pe&gt;Stalin&lt;/pe&gt; had for a long time had in hand [00:08:35]&lt;pe&gt;Kim Il-sung's&lt;/pe&gt; declaration that he intended to invade the South.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:08:40]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:08:50]It was in &lt;da&gt;March, 1949&lt;/da&gt; that &lt;pe&gt;Kim Il-sung&lt;/pe&gt; had informed &lt;pe&gt;Stalin&lt;/pe&gt; of his [00:08:55]plans to conquer &lt;pl&gt;South Korea&lt;/pl&gt;. &lt;pe&gt;Stalin&lt;/pe&gt;, busy with European expansion [00:09:00]plans, gave wary support and handed &lt;pe&gt;Kim&lt;/pe&gt; over to &lt;pe&gt;Defense Minister Bulganin&lt;/pe&gt; [00:09:05]to help with military equipment. A month later, [00:09:10]&lt;pe&gt;Kim&lt;/pe&gt; shared his plans with Communist Party Chairman &lt;pe&gt;Mao Zedong&lt;/pe&gt;, asking for the [00:09:15]same support. &lt;pe&gt;Mao&lt;/pe&gt; was occupied with [00:09:20]consolidating his victory over the Chinese Nationalists in the mainland but also provided guarded but [00:09:25]important bolstering. Then the &lt;pl&gt;U.S.&lt;/pl&gt; blundered. In [00:09:30]&lt;da&gt;January of 1950&lt;/da&gt;, American Secretary of State &lt;pe&gt;Dean Acheson&lt;/pe&gt; spoke to the National [00:09:35]Press Club in &lt;pl&gt;Washington, D.C.&lt;/pl&gt;, outlining the West's perimeter of defense. [00:09:40]Because neither &lt;pe&gt;MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt; nor the joint chiefs had identified &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; as a vital [00:09:45]interest, he left &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; out of the picture. The omission [00:09:50]pealed like thunder in the communist world.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;DONALD P. GREGG&lt;/pe&gt; CHAIRMAN OF THE KOREA SOCIETY&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Donald P. Gregg&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Kim&lt;/pe&gt; again asked for [00:09:55]support. &lt;pe&gt;Stalin&lt;/pe&gt; got in touch with &lt;pe&gt;Mao&lt;/pe&gt; and the immediate question was, "What will the [00:10:00]Americans do?" And their collective judgment was, the Americans would do nothing.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:10:05]It is almost inconceivable that the massive size of the invasion forces building [00:10:10]up across the North Korean border could have been missed by Western intelligence. [00:10:15]But despite the loud warnings of lonely individual voices, [00:10:20]it was.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. ROD PASCHALL&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt; (RET.) EDITOR, MILITARY HISTORY QUARTERLY&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Rod Paschall&lt;/sp&gt; [00:10:25]The &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; had armed South Korea's army as little more than a constabulary, only [00:10:30]a peacekeeping or a police force. Part of the reason was the fact that [00:10:35]the intelligence supplied by the Central Intelligence Agency [00:10:40]about the North Koreans was totally flawed. Ah, a few short months [00:10:45]before the war, they are carrying only 36,000, ah, troops in the North Korean Army. [00:10:50]The fact is there were 136,000 troops, virtually no [00:10:55]information about the large number of tanks, well over 170 first-line tanks [00:11:00]that the North Koreans had.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Kim&lt;/pe&gt; confidently [00:11:05]informed &lt;pe&gt;Mao&lt;/pe&gt; that the army had promised the conquest would be completed two to three weeks. [00:11:10]He did not expect to need any open help from his brother communists. [00:11:15]The early morning of &lt;da&gt;June 25th, [00:11:20]1950&lt;/da&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;South Korea's&lt;/pl&gt; 38th Parallel rocked with the crushing North Korean artillery and [00:11:25]mortar barrage. Seven combat-ready divisions, supported [00:11:30]by an armored brigade of &lt;pl&gt;Russia's&lt;/pl&gt; formidable T-34 tanks, achieved complete tactical and [00:11:35]strategic surprise.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:11:40]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:11:45]Under a third of the South Korean Army was deployed to the front. [00:11:50]It possessed less than six days' ammunition. More [00:11:55]than 200 Russian-supplied Yak-9 fighters and ground attack bombers hurtled at Southern [00:12:00]targets.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:12:05]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Rhee's&lt;/pe&gt; defending army of 95,000, deliberately-[00:12:10]denied offensive aircraft, tanks, anti-tank weapons and heavy artillery, [00:12:15]were quickly in critical trouble against the Red armor.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;BEVIN ALEXANDER&lt;/pe&gt; LECTURER:MILITARY HISTORY LONGWOOD COLLEGE, &lt;pl&gt;VIRGINIA&lt;/pl&gt;&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Bevin Alexander&lt;/sp&gt; [00:12:20]They simply lined these tanks up on these little narrow roads, [00:12:25]one behind the other, which in normal conditions would have caused a disaster, and simply started [00:12:30]South. And because there was nothing who could stop the tanks, the North Korean Army actually just [00:12:35]blew through the South Korean Army and that's what made it successful in the first stages of the war.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:12:40]Led by their invincible tanks, four communist Spearheads [00:12:45]drove south through gaps in the hills. The communist divisions were supported by [00:12:50]1,600 guns as their forces surged down the ancient invasion route [00:12:55]of the &lt;pl&gt;Uijeongbu&lt;/pl&gt; Corridor. The southern towns and cities began to fall, [00:13:00]and the North had the Southern capital of &lt;pl&gt;Seoul&lt;/pl&gt; in its sights. [00:13:05]Not since the attack at Pearl Harbor had the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; [00:13:10]experienced such utter bewilderment and unpreparedness. The [00:13:15]attack had been proceeding for nine hours before &lt;pe&gt;President Truman&lt;/pe&gt; was informed. [00:13:20]The newspapers were blaring information before the government had it.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. JOSEPH H. ALEXANDER&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (RET.) HISTORIAN&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Col. Joseph H. Alexander&lt;/sp&gt; [00:13:25]We figured that with, ah, the dawn of atomic [00:13:30]warfare and, ah, jet bombers that we would not need ground forces and [00:13:35]close-combat forces. We were dead wrong. We had allowed our, our fighting [00:13:40]forces to deteriorate, ah, to be downsized and eliminated, [00:13:45]and to be underequipped and poorly equipped.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:13:50]That &lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt; had its military giant in World War II in the Pacific on hand [00:13:55]in &lt;pl&gt;Tokyo&lt;/pl&gt; just a few hundred miles from the fighting, was not as reassuring as it seemed. [00:14:00]The mighty five-star hero who was now Supreme [00:14:05]Commander in the Far East, was as unprepared as anyone. [00:14:10]That &lt;pe&gt;General Douglas MacArthur's&lt;/pe&gt; thin American forces occupying &lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt; [00:14:15]were just a shell of a fighting army, was, in great measure, his fault. [00:14:20]Training, equipping and conditioning had been all but totally ignored in the endless [00:14:25]tours of bars, officers' clubs and geisha houses in a comfortable, [00:14:30]subjugated &lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.&lt;p&gt;[00:14:35]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Hermann&lt;/sp&gt; The American leadership scrambled to react to the North Korean attack. [00:14:40]The American policy called the "Truman Doctrine," seemed to call for [00:14:45]American support of anti-communism without commitment of forces. [00:14:50]But the feisty American President who made the policy could interpret it [00:14:55]any way he wanted.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;LT. GEN. BERNARD E. TRAINOR&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (RET.)&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Lt. Gen. Bernard E. Trainor&lt;/sp&gt; There is no telling what a President of the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; can do. And [00:15:00]&lt;pe&gt;Harry Truman&lt;/pe&gt;, despite his doctrine, despite what the Secretary of State had stated [00:15:05]in terms of, ah, &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; being outside of our defensive sphere [00:15:10]said, "By golly, this is not gonna stand and we're gonna kick these fellows [00:15:15]back." So he turned topsy-turvy a policy that had been very, very carefully crafted [00:15:20]three, for about three to four years. He kicked that out the window in one minute when he told [00:15:25]&lt;pe&gt;Douglas MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt; to go after these guys.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; There was [00:15:30]one more force that no national politician could ignore as it did as much [00:15:35]to drive &lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt; into this unexpected, unwanted bloodbath as [00:15:40]anything in the whole sorry tragedy.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Joseph McCarthy&lt;/sp&gt; If we, unless we, make [00:15:45]sure that there is no infiltration of our government, [00:15:50]then just as certain as you sit there, [00:15:55]in the period of our lives, you will see a Red [00:16:00]world.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:16:05]As the North Korean surprise juggernaut shredded the South's badly divisioned [00:16:10]defenses in late &lt;da&gt;June of 1950&lt;/da&gt;, the &lt;pe&gt;Truman&lt;/pe&gt; administration found itself [00:16:15]impelled to action, action anchored in principle and played against the background [00:16:20]of bitter controversy within the nation's government. [00:16:25]When the communist forces of &lt;pe&gt;Mao Zedong&lt;/pe&gt; had driven [00:16:30]&lt;pe&gt;Chiang Kai-shek's&lt;/pe&gt; Nationalist Army off the Chinese mainland to the island of &lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt; in &lt;da&gt;1949&lt;/da&gt;, [00:16:35]howls of rage began in &lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt;. The so-called "&lt;pl&gt;China&lt;/pl&gt; [00:16:40]lobby" were demanding, "Who lost &lt;pl&gt;China&lt;/pl&gt;?"&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;LT. GEN. BERNARD E. TRAINOR&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (RET.)&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Lt. Gen. Bernard E. Trainor&lt;/sp&gt; Well, the wartime [00:16:45]propaganda that worked from &lt;da&gt;1937&lt;/da&gt; right, ah, until the fall of &lt;pl&gt;China&lt;/pl&gt;, ah, was [00:16:50]focused on the nationalists as being the hope for a democratic and, and [00:16:55]unified &lt;pl&gt;China&lt;/pl&gt;. And then all of a sudden, out of the mountains, comes [00:17:00]the 8th Route Army, these communists, and in no time they have conquered the [00:17:05]country. They couldn't believe that &lt;pe&gt;Chiang's&lt;/pe&gt; venality [00:17:10]and corruption and the weakness of, of the nationalist government was to fault because they are told [00:17:15]how well they had done, so there must have been another reason. The other [00:17:20]reason was because they were betrayed by American statesmen, [00:17:25]who were really secret communists and this is something that &lt;pe&gt;General MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt; was able to profit on.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Joseph McCarthy&lt;/sp&gt; [00:17:30]Even if there's only one communist in the State Department, that would still be one communist [00:17:35]too many.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Senator McCarthy's&lt;/pe&gt; vitriolic accusations of treason would not [00:17:40]be likely ignored in any decision for resolute action against what was seen as a Red [00:17:45]onslaught.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Joseph McCarthy&lt;/sp&gt; What the President thinks his job is.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; While &lt;pe&gt;Rhee&lt;/pe&gt; begged [00:17:50]the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; for help, the Americans asked for a meeting of the UN Security [00:17:55]Council to consider moves against the aggression. No Soviet veto would [00:18:00]materialize because the Soviet delegate, &lt;pe&gt;Jacob Malik&lt;/pe&gt;, had on January [00:18:05]13th, walked out of the Council to protest the UN refusal to seat [00:18:10]Communist &lt;pl&gt;China&lt;/pl&gt; in place of the Chinese Nationalists. He was still absent [00:18:15]on June 25th. A UN resolution condemning the attack [00:18:20]and calling for North Korean withdrawal was passed by a unanimous vote. [00:18:25]The United Nations was going to war.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;DONALD P. GREGG&lt;/pe&gt; CHAIRMAN OF THE KOREA SOCIETY&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Donald P. Gregg&lt;/sp&gt; I think the United [00:18:30]Nations' response to the invasion of, of &lt;pl&gt;South Korea&lt;/pl&gt; [00:18:35]is probably the greatest hour in terms of, ah, the [00:18:40]United Nations' lifetime in terms of its response to aggression. [00:18:45]And 16 nations, ah, sent forces to fight, ah, in [00:18:50]&lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Although the troops, [00:18:55]ships and air forces of the Allied nations that joined the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; were small in comparative [00:19:00]numbers, they included the cream of many hallowed fighting units and would [00:19:05]equip themselves bloodily and gloriously.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;DR. EDWARD J. MAROLDA&lt;/pe&gt; NAVAL HISTORIAN&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Dr. Edward J. Marolda&lt;/sp&gt; [00:19:10]One of the first things the US Navy did in league with the other nine navies that were involved was [00:19:15]to establish absolute control of the sea in the &lt;pl&gt;Yellow Sea&lt;/pl&gt; and the &lt;pl&gt;Sea of Japan&lt;/pl&gt;. [00:19:20]We could use that patrol of the sea for carrier strikes along the length of [00:19:25]the Korean coastline for naval gunfire, that is, bringing destroyers and [00:19:30]battleships and any other gunfighter ships close aboard and firing on targets [00:19:35]ashore. We could use, ah, our carriers for closer support of our troops in [00:19:40]battle.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; The fleet also became a powerful weapon of policy.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Dr. Edward J. Marolda&lt;/sp&gt; [00:19:45]&lt;pe&gt;Truman&lt;/pe&gt; had pretty much written off &lt;pe&gt;Chiang Kai-Shek&lt;/pe&gt; and the Nationalists in [00:19:50]&lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt; and he thought &lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt; would, would fall at any moment to the Communists. [00:19:55]But when the Korean War developed, it, it changed it overnight, and &lt;pe&gt;Truman&lt;/pe&gt; had [00:20:00]figured that he could not afford to lose &lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt; because of the perception of the peoples in the [00:20:05]area and the people in the world that, ah, the Western position was falling. [00:20:10]So he dispatched the 7th Fleet from &lt;pl&gt;Subic Bay&lt;/pl&gt;. Ah, they were en route to [00:20:15]&lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; to be involved in, in the operations there. But on the way, they passed by &lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt; [00:20:20]and they sent 29 aircraft into the strait between &lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt; [00:20:25]and the mainland to signal &lt;pe&gt;Mao Zedong&lt;/pe&gt; that we would not stand for an invasion of [00:20:30]&lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:20:35]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Dr. Edward J. Marolda&lt;/sp&gt; That was one of the things that concerned &lt;pe&gt;Mao Zedong&lt;/pe&gt; at the outset of the [00:20:40]war. That this was not just an effort by the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; and &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; to contain [00:20:45]what's happening in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; but it, it was actually part of a concerted effort to undermine [00:20:50]the Communist government in &lt;pl&gt;Beijing&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Just two days after the [00:20:55]attack, the Republic of Korea government and army headquarters and the U.S. Embassy and Military [00:21:00]Advisory Group, were leaving &lt;pl&gt;Seoul&lt;/pl&gt; to move south. The American [00:21:05]advisers tried desperately to stop the South Koreans from destroying the bridges over the &lt;pl&gt;River Han&lt;/pl&gt; before [00:21:10]thousands of its soldiers and civilians could cross to safety. But with [00:21:15]disgraceful callousness and incompetence, the bridges were blown while loaded with the [00:21:20]fleeing.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:21:25]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; As many as 800 people died and much of the [00:21:30]crumbling Republic of Korea Army was trapped north of the Han. [00:21:35]The retreating troops that [00:21:40]were finally able to float across the river did so without transport, supplies and [00:21:45]what heavy weapons they had. Organization was vanishing. [00:21:50]&lt;pl&gt;Seoul&lt;/pl&gt; fell by the 28th. Of the [00:21:55]98,000 men in the ROK Army, 34,000 were already killed, captured [00:22:00]or missing.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:22:05]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:22:10]The scraped-together obsolescent aircraft of the [00:22:15]U.S. Far East Command, provided the only instant help available to the reeling [00:22:20]South Koreans. And there were big problems.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;DR. RICHARD P. HALLION&lt;/pe&gt; THE AIR FORCE HISTORIAN&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Dr. Richard P. Hallion&lt;/sp&gt; The North Koreans [00:22:25]advanced so rapidly that they overran a lot of the available airfields and a lot of the areas where [00:22:30]we could have used the emergency airfields in the South. And so we were reduced very, very quickly [00:22:35]from the United States Air Force standpoint to providing combat power, ah, from [00:22:40]&lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Although the old World War II [00:22:45]P-51s, Corsairs, B-26s joined the [00:22:50]early jets to gain air control and make the roads of &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; an increasingly costly place for the enemy [00:22:55]to be, the North Koreans deigned to hide their tanks because the [00:23:00]mere sight of them sent the ROK forces fleeing. [00:23:05]By June 30th, &lt;pe&gt;MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt; had personally inspected the disintegrating front and quickly [00:23:10]demanded U.S. ground forces to be committed to the Peninsula. [00:23:15]Four infantry divisions, the 24th, 25th, 2nd [00:23:20]Infantry and 1st Cavalry were dispatched to &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;. [00:23:25]The administration discarded the idea of a declaration of war, deciding this to be [00:23:30]a mere police action. An appalling number of young [00:23:35]policemen, stepping ashore in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;, would not leave this unknown land [00:23:40]alive.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:23:45]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; If Americans had any [00:23:55]doubt that they were in a real war in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;, it was dispelled by a call-up of [00:24:00]reserve units and an extension of the military draft. [00:24:05]&lt;pe&gt;Truman's&lt;/pe&gt; decision to fight enjoyed wide public support, [00:24:10]but not necessarily among the public that was going to fight, especially the World [00:24:15]War II veterans and reservists.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;LT COL.SHERMAN W. PRATT&lt;/pe&gt; (RET.) AUTHOR:"DECISIVE BATTLES OF THE KOREAN WAR"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Lt. Col. Sherman W. Pratt&lt;/sp&gt; [00:24:20]They were desperate for bodies in &lt;pe&gt;Korea&lt;/pe&gt; in those days, there were units that was [00:24:25]in the fighting that was all under strength and desperate and they, many people said, "Well, [00:24:30]they will never send &lt;pe&gt;Pratt&lt;/pe&gt; because he has 10 campaigns and three years in frontline duty in World [00:24:35]War II. Suddenly, my orders for &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; came in.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;JOSEPH A. CAPPELLA&lt;/pe&gt; S. SGT. &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt;&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Joseph A. Cappella&lt;/sp&gt; [00:24:40]Hey, I was a reservist and the [00:24:45]reservists were what you might call the "minuteman" of this century.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:24:50]As so often through history, luck granted [00:24:55]&lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt; a first-rate top leadership at a critical moment. &lt;pe&gt;Truman&lt;/pe&gt; was tough, [00:25:00]smart, decisive and always open to good advice. And he got plenty of [00:25:05]that from his Secretary of State &lt;pe&gt;Dean Acheson&lt;/pe&gt;, the brilliant &lt;pe&gt;George Marshall&lt;/pe&gt; and [00:25:10]&lt;pe&gt;Omar Bradley&lt;/pe&gt;, head of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. All had been hardened [00:25:15]in the political and military forge of World War II. [00:25:20]As for &lt;pe&gt;MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt;, the old giant seemed 10 years younger [00:25:25]for he now saw it as his destiny, not just to stop an aggression, but [00:25:30]to use all the weapons and power of the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; to confront and utterly defeat all of [00:25:35]world communism on this battlefield. That [00:25:40]such a war might expand and run out of control and into atomic war did not concern him, [00:25:45]and many shared his view.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. JOSEPH H. ALEXANDER&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (RET.) AUTHOR:"SEA SOLDIERS OF THE COLD WAR"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Col. Joseph H. Alexander&lt;/sp&gt; The question of whether &lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt; would use [00:25:50]atomic weapons in the execution of this war, ah, was not a [00:25:55]major debate. Only five years earlier, we had used two of our weapons effectively to [00:26:00]end World War II. We didn't have this, ah, large buildup of, ah, aversion [00:26:05]to that type of warfare. Ah, it was just one of weapon in our inventory that we could [00:26:10]use, ah, effectively.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:26:15]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Would the Russian and Chinese giants intervene? &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;, [00:26:20]&lt;pl&gt;Japan&lt;/pl&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;Berlin&lt;/pl&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;Taiwan&lt;/pl&gt;; they had their choice. [00:26:25]But the communists had been shocked at how wrong they had been about the &lt;pl&gt;United States'&lt;/pl&gt; resolve to defend [00:26:30]&lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;, and the stakes were too high to be wrong again.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;LT. GEN. BERNARD E. TRAINOR&lt;/pe&gt;/, USMC (RET.)&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Lt. Gen. Bernard E. Trainor&lt;/sp&gt; [00:26:35]If they were chess players, then we were poker players and they found the [00:26:40]&lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; very dangerous because we, they never knew when we're gonna bluff, [00:26:45]when we're gonna call and they knew that we had this enormous potential, this enormous [00:26:50]firepower to bring to them.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; But it looked like the last thing the [00:26:55]North Koreans needed was help. These were first-class fighters with first-class [00:27:00]tactics. And it was beginning to look as though the first trickle of American troops beginning to [00:27:05]arrive at the southern port of &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt;, might be arriving just in time to take [00:27:10]part in an Asiatic Dunkirk. The Americans [00:27:15]were not ready to fight, much less to win.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Joseph A. Cappella&lt;/sp&gt; [00:27:20]Our captain advised us that they did not have any ammunition for us. [00:27:25]And if we were attacked we should go to Tent No. 4 and get [00:27:30]four rounds of ammunition and one hand grenade. And that's what I remember [00:27:35]about the first day I arrived in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; The Army's [00:27:40]24th Infantry Division, thrown piecemeal into battle, bore the brunt of [00:27:45]trying to stop the North Korean steamroller. Typical of the near [00:27:50]hopeless fight was the fate of what was called "Task Force Smith," [00:27:55]a lightly armed force of 406 officers and men commanded by &lt;pe&gt;Lieutenant [00:28:00]Colonel Charles Smith&lt;/pe&gt; that was thrown in against the wave of communist troops and [00:28:05]tanks. Their outmoded 2.36-inch bazooka rockets bounced [00:28:10]off the Russian made T-34s like BBs. Even direct fire by [00:28:15]their few puny 105s was no match for the thick armor. [00:28:20]The North Koreans went around them, behind them and through them. [00:28:25]The only thing Task Force Smith could buy with the loss of half its men was [00:28:30]three days' time. But it was time that was needed [00:28:35]beyond all other things. As the [00:28:40]24th tried to delay the main attack, six more North Korean divisions [00:28:45]were driving back to bloodied ROK Army in the mountainous center of the country. [00:28:50]On each coast, far from the main attack, the communists sped south, [00:28:55]intent on surrounding the South Koreans and Americans. On the west coast, [00:29:00]the enemy faced only scattered South Korean policemen. The stage was set [00:29:05]for one of the greatest encirclements and slaughters of the 20th century. [00:29:10]To the bewildered reservists, [00:29:15]draftees and World War II retreads, the next weeks were a numbing procession of [00:29:20]defeat, retreat, ignorance and confusion. [00:29:25]They saw no more of the war than what was shooting at their own company, squad or platoon.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;RAYMOND E. DONNELLY JR.&lt;/pe&gt; 24TH DIVISION KOREAN WAR&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Raymond E. Donnelly Jr.&lt;/sp&gt; [00:29:30]Oh, I had no idea of what was going on. I had no idea where I was. Thank [00:29:35]God my wife used to send me clippings from the newspaper and that's when I knew what the shape of &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; was like [00:29:40]and where I was, because she put a little arrow and she'll say, "This is where you are."&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:29:45]The all-enveloping enemy was well led, [00:29:50]determined and infinitely better equipped. The [00:29:55]M-24 light tanks that the &lt;pl&gt;United States&lt;/pl&gt; had landed melted away in the summer heat before the [00:30:00]T-34s.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. HARRY J. MAIHAFER&lt;/pe&gt;, USA (RET.) AUTHOR:"FROM THE HUDSON TO THE YALU"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Col. Harry J. Maihafer&lt;/sp&gt; They said, "Well, heavy tanks cannot [00:30:05]operate in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;. And by the time I got there, of course, the T-34 tanks [00:30:10]which were Russian, ah, heavy ones or medium at least, had come down and shot [00:30:15]the devil out of everything. And, ah, the tank battalion that I joined had lost [00:30:20]11 of their 17 tanks in one day and, ah, by the time I got there, they only had two [00:30:25]left. The North Koreans were good. They had been well trained. They [00:30:30]had, uh, a one basic tactic, which was when they ran in, into opposition they would just overflow to the [00:30:35]flanks and, and get behind us. And pretty soon, the unit would be cut off and [00:30:40]you'd have to fight your way back out of it again. I remember the first time I heard the [00:30:45]term "bug out." Ah, the Lieutenant was bringing me back up to, ah, [00:30:50]position on the nick of time, pointed down to a trail and said, "That's the bug out route." [00:30:55]And I didn't know what that meant, and I turned, pretty soon found that that was a very [00:31:00]common term, "bug out," meaning, they, they're behind us, there, every man for himself. [00:31:05]It's a pretty sorry state at that time, but it was understandable.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. ROD PASCHALL&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt; (RET.) AUTHOR: "&lt;pl&gt;KOREA&lt;/pl&gt;: WITNESS TO WAR"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Col. Rod Paschall&lt;/sp&gt; [00:31:10]Those that had good officers performed well, in [00:31:15]some cases magnificently. Those who had [00:31:20]mediocre or poor officers, uh, failed miserably. There was a [00:31:25]desperation on the part of the, ah, soldiers within those units that had poor leadership, [00:31:30]a desperation for decent leadership. It takes a very skilled unit [00:31:35]to do a withdrawal well because you have to do it in echelons, moving one echelon through [00:31:40]another one and committing, uh, successive delays. You have to be a topnotch [00:31:45]professional to do it, and the forces with ah, that we had in the early, ah, weeks of the [00:31:50]war in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt; were not professional by any stretch of imagination.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:31:55]The retreats south to the Naktong River became so desperate [00:32:00]that &lt;pe&gt;Major General William Dean&lt;/pe&gt; found himself fighting as a bazooka man to dam the Red tide. [00:32:05]With telephone wires cut and radios failing, [00:32:10]&lt;pe&gt;Dean&lt;/pe&gt; picked up some survivors of Task Force Smith and fought in [00:32:15]disarray. Withdrawals without orders began with equipment abandoned. [00:32:20]Repeatedly, a raging &lt;pe&gt;Dean&lt;/pe&gt; relieved wavering officers who tried to stabilize his blocking positions. [00:32:25]&lt;pe&gt;Dean&lt;/pe&gt; would finally be taken prisoner and endure [00:32:30]a bitter confinement. [00:32:35]&lt;pe&gt;Marguerite Higgins&lt;/pe&gt; of the New York Herald Tribune wrote, "I saw young Americans [00:32:40]turn and bolt in battle, or throw down their arms, cursing their government for what [00:32:45]they thought was embroilment in a hopeless cause." [00:32:50]The night seemed blacker than ever for the UN forces. [00:32:55]But a new dawn was coming closer.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[00:33:00]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:33:05]As the North Koreans continued to drive the UN forces [00:33:10]southward toward the sea in the middle of a searing &lt;da&gt;July of 1950&lt;/da&gt;, [00:33:15]the Communists were about to find out that the pursuer's position could also deteriorate [00:33:20]quickly and insidiously.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. JOSEPH H. ALEXANDER&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (RET.) HISTORIAN&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Joseph H. Alexander&lt;/sp&gt; [00:33:25]The North Koreans' only weakness as they swept further and further south [00:33:30]down the Peninsula was the increasing vulnerability of their long lines [00:33:35]of, of supply. Now true, their troops could live, they boasted, on three rice [00:33:40]bowls a day, but it was still an army and a mechanized army at that. [00:33:45]They needed fuel and ammo and repair parts and people.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; Specially, they [00:33:50]needed people. The staggering UN forces with the South Koreans bearing the brunt of the [00:33:55]fight were inflicting more fearful casualties upon their onrushing enemy than anyone suspected. [00:34:00]Airpower had begun to make the daylight hideously [00:34:05]dangerous. And new [00:34:10]3.5-inch bazookas and harder-hitting tank guns were beginning to slice through the North's dwindling army. [00:34:15]The Communists [00:34:20]had sustained 58,000 casualties. [00:34:25]Just as ominous for the Reds, the blood of [00:34:30]the UN armies had bought enough time to bring an increasingly decisive sea lift of men and [00:34:35]material across the water to &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; for the fast-compressing [00:34:40]defensive perimeter. Coordinated combat leadership [00:34:45]began to fall into place. &lt;pe&gt;General Walton Walker&lt;/pe&gt;, sawed[00:34:50]off and salty and a highly regarded combat veteran in the World War II, arrived to [00:34:55]take charge of eight army ground forces: American, Korean and Allied. [00:35:00]&lt;pe&gt;MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt; was formally appointed [00:35:05]Commander-in-Chief of the United Nations' command and &lt;pe&gt;Syngman [00:35:10]Rhee&lt;/pe&gt; placed all his forces under UN leadership. [00:35:15]The North also exacerbated its own growing troubles. [00:35:20]News filtering out of the conquered territory [00:35:25]told of an unspeakable North Korean butchery turned loose against entire villages [00:35:30]of Koreans suspected of Southern sympathies.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:35:35]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:35:45]The atrocities did not stop with the civilians. [00:35:50]In mounting counterattacks to slow the [00:35:55]advance, the Americans found that the North Koreans had bound with barbed wire and then murdered [00:36:00]American prisoners. [00:36:05]Instantly, U.S. soldiers fought harder, [00:36:10]both from rage and the realization that surrender offered little safety. [00:36:15]A United States Army trained to fight in a material-rich network [00:36:20]of supporting arms, was unable to come to grips with having its flanks hanging in the [00:36:25]air. Enemy success would solve their problem. [00:36:30]The key city of &lt;pl&gt;Taejon&lt;/pl&gt; fell and the enemy [00:36:35]hooked around it, sweeping toward &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; from both the north and the west. [00:36:40]Now, the UN forces tucked themselves backward behind the loop of the Naktong [00:36:45]River and upon the final piece of high ground before the Korean Straits. [00:36:50]This formed the suddenly solidified defensive semicircle in [00:36:55]the southeast corner of the Korean Peninsula to go into history as the &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; Perimeter. [00:37:00]The war of maneuver was over. Battered as they were, [00:37:05]the Americans were now braced shoulder-to-shoulder, fighting their kind of war at last. [00:37:10]But you could not have told the exhausted soldiers that things were about to get better.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Harry J. Maihafer&lt;/sp&gt; [00:37:15]The platoon was down to a handful of men before [00:37:20]we got our replacements. I think only three of the original platoon were still alive [00:37:25]that had, ah, landed in, in &lt;pl&gt;Korea&lt;/pl&gt;.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. HARRY SUMMERS&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt; (RET.) COL. 21ST INFANTRY ASSOC.&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Harry Summers&lt;/sp&gt; [00:37:30]As you may know, a rifle company is the coolest organization in the world [00:37:35]because when a new person comes in and needs help and needs guidance, [00:37:40]and is lost and needs friends in the worst way, no one will talk to him. They won't even [00:37:45]speak to him, they'll walk away from him, they don't wanna know him. [00:37:50]Because unless you've been blooded, you're not part of the unit.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:37:55]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; For [00:38:00]six terrible weeks, the Battle of the &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; Perimeter raged. Again [00:38:05]and again, the enemy seemed on the verge of making the breach in the lines that would carry them to &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; [00:38:10]and the UN apocalypse. But [00:38:15]each time the patchwork defensive lines made the desperate improvisations, [00:38:20]that held for another day. &lt;pe&gt;General [00:38:25]Walker&lt;/pe&gt; ordered, "There will be no more retreating. This is not going to be a &lt;pl&gt;Dunkirk&lt;/pl&gt; [00:38:30]or a Bataan. We must fight to the end."&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;COL. HARRY J. MAIHAFER&lt;/pe&gt;, &lt;pl&gt;USA&lt;/pl&gt; (RET.) AUTHOR:"FROM THE HUDSON TO THE YALU"&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Harry J. Maihafer&lt;/sp&gt; [00:38:35]"Stand or die," says &lt;pe&gt;Walker&lt;/pe&gt;. "If we don't stand, it will be the greatest [00:38:40]bloodbath known to &lt;pl&gt;America&lt;/pl&gt;. This had very little sales appeal for those of us [00:38:45]hurrying forward to join the team."&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; If the battle was raging in place [00:38:50]at the front line, it was being inexorably won on the docks of the still open port of [00:38:55]&lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt;. The potent M-26 medium tanks were being unloaded[00:39:00]. Heavy artillery, always an American master specialty, [00:39:05]began coming ashore in quantity with mountains of shells. And most [00:39:10]critically the men were coming, some of them primed for action.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:39:15]The arrival of the well-trained [00:39:20]air-ground marine brigade loaded with NCO veterans of World War II, [00:39:25]brought in a military professionalism, still forming in the units that have been thrown [00:39:30]pell-mell into the fighting.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;&lt;pe&gt;CONO LOMBARDI&lt;/pe&gt; VETERAN, KOREAN WAR&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Cono Lombardi&lt;/sp&gt; You had to expect the way they did things. [00:39:35]They trained as a unit, they stayed as a unit. They had a gung-ho attitude [00:39:40]about them, always hung tough. When they went [00:39:45]down to scramble nets and we took the gangplank out.&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:39:50]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:39:55]It was a tribute to the headlong ferocity of the North Korean [00:40:00]attacks and an indictment of the UN forces that it was still widely [00:40:05]held that the perimeter defenders were an outnumbered band beset by limitless hoards [00:40:10]of attackers. But the fact was that by now, [00:40:15]the UN forces before &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; outnumbered the surviving besiegers.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:40:20]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:40:25]The headlong, near suicidal nature of the North Korean assault had exposed it [00:40:30]to relentless air interdiction by UN Air Forces. UN airmen [00:40:35]held the skies uncontested and grew rapidly in numbers and competence. [00:40:40]With envelopment tactics now [00:40:45]impossible, the North Korean waves squandered themselves against powerful and well-directed [00:40:50]artillery. The ROK units [00:40:55]that could once have been counted on to collapse when surrounded, were now fighting [00:41:00]hard. And while the North was not [00:41:05]replacing its losses, the ever-shuttling ships into &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; were building UN might. [00:41:10]Even so, the [00:41:15]95,000 men that &lt;pe&gt;Walker&lt;/pe&gt; disposed on paper, were still hard put to [00:41:20]defend 130 long miles of perimeter against the skillful and tenacious enemy. [00:41:25]A World War II veteran [00:41:30]colonel was brutal about his men's continuing shortcomings, saying, "They've spent [00:41:35]a lot of time listening to lectures on the difference between Communism and Americanism when [00:41:40]somebody ought to have been telling them how to clear a machine gun when it jams. [00:41:45]The US Army has soldiers so road-bound that the soldiers have almost lost the use of their legs."&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:41:50]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:41:55]Arriving troops had by now a good idea of what their chances [00:42:00]were in the different units and the infantry was where you didn't wanna be.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pa&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Cono Lombardi&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:05]At the time we arrived at the 2nd [00:42:10]Division replacement center where they replace all the different outfits that were low in men, [00:42:15]we knew the infantry was taking very heavy casualties. Ah, we had infantry [00:42:20]on the west, who were assigned the artillery. It was like [00:42:25]God came down and said, "You will live." We spontaneously formed a circle [00:42:30]like a ring around the roses and chanted, "We're gonna make it, we're [00:42:35]gonna make it."&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:40]On August 31st, the North Koreans [00:42:45]gathered all the strength they had left and flung it against the thin, wavering UN line. [00:42:50]Their courage was unquestioned, their tactics a disaster. [00:42:55]In a seesaw battle over the next week with breakthroughs often inches away [00:43:00]and &lt;pe&gt;Walker&lt;/pe&gt; forced to consider a general withdrawal, [00:43:05]the Northerners broke themselves on withering UN firepower.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:43:10]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:43:15]The enemy had snapped the overstretched rubbberband of men, food, guns and [00:43:20]ammunitions stretching back north. For now, the &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; Perimeter [00:43:25]had held. [00:43:30]And miraculously, there began to be whispers of a brilliant new offensive [00:43:35]operation being put together personally by America's legendary God of War, [00:43:40]&lt;pe&gt;Douglas MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;THE KOREAN WAR FIRE &amp; ICE Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;Lou Reda&lt;/pe&gt; Produced By &lt;pe&gt;Mort Zimmerman&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Vincent Mondillo&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Tracey A. Connor&lt;/pe&gt; Written By &lt;pe&gt;Norman Stahl&lt;/pe&gt; with &lt;pe&gt;Joseph Alexander&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Rod Paschall&lt;/pe&gt; Edited By &lt;pe&gt;Tracey A. Connor&lt;/pe&gt; Executive in Charge of Production &lt;pe&gt;Sammy Jackson&lt;/pe&gt; Narrated By &lt;pe&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/pe&gt; Post Production Supervisor &lt;pe&gt;Paul Lewis&lt;/pe&gt; Special Thanks To &lt;pe&gt;Col. Richard T. Poore&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (Ret.) &lt;pe&gt;Mr. Martin Russ&lt;/pe&gt; The Korean Society &lt;pe&gt;Col. Warren Wiedhahn&lt;/pe&gt; Military Historical Tours &lt;pe&gt;Joseph Calabria&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Cono Lombardi&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Corp. A.F. Kiviehan&lt;/pe&gt; Chapter Of The Korean War Veterans Assoc. &lt;pe&gt;Col. Michael F. Monigan&lt;/pe&gt; Marine Corps Photo Archives &lt;pe&gt;M.E. Englander&lt;/pe&gt; Naval Media Center U.S. Navy Public Affairs &lt;pe&gt;Adm. Thomas Jurkowsky&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Lt. Scott Allen&lt;/pe&gt; Special Consultant &lt;pe&gt;Gen. Edwin H. Simmons&lt;/pe&gt; Archival Resources U.S. Marine Corps U.S. Navy U.S. Army The National Archives M-25 Productions Lou Reda Archives Department of Defense &lt;pe&gt;Bill Barr&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Robert Melhorn&lt;/pe&gt; For Lou Reda Productions Graphics &lt;pe&gt;Paul Lewis&lt;/pe&gt; Map Design &lt;pe&gt;Matt Stahl&lt;/pe&gt; Trancripts &lt;pe&gt;Sharon Stahl&lt;/pe&gt; Office Coordinators &lt;pe&gt;Alison Dorshimer&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Jeanette Reyes&lt;/pe&gt; Duplication &lt;pe&gt;Tom Schinstine&lt;/pe&gt; Archives &lt;pe&gt;Chris Futrics&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;John McCullough&lt;/pe&gt; Production Assistants &lt;pe&gt;Lou Reda II&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Mark Tergesen&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Stacy L. Schiomann&lt;/pe&gt; Executive Administration &lt;pe&gt;Mrs. Timmie Reda&lt;/pe&gt; Assistant To Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;Scott Reda&lt;/pe&gt; Opening Title Design &lt;pe&gt;Lauri Salladay&lt;/pe&gt; So! much design Additional Elements &lt;pe&gt;Rob Cazin&lt;/pe&gt; So! much design Music by PROMUSIC Audio EFX Design &lt;pe&gt;Scott Delaney&lt;/pe&gt; Audio Plus Video Additional Music by Swing'N Dixie &lt;pe&gt;Parke Frankenfield&lt;/pe&gt; Orchestra Edited on MEDIA 100 MEDIA This program produced in &lt;pl&gt;Easton, Pennsylvania&lt;/pl&gt; at the Lou Reda Studios &lt;da&gt;1950&lt;/da&gt;-&lt;da&gt;1953&lt;/da&gt; &lt;pl&gt;UNITED STATES OF AMERICA&lt;/pl&gt; &lt;da&gt;2000&lt;/da&gt;-&lt;da&gt;2003&lt;/da&gt; COMMEMORATION 50 ANIVERSARY OF THE KOREAN WAR COMMEMORATION 50th Anniversary of the Korean War Commemoration 50th Anniversary of the Korean War Commemoration Committee &lt;pe&gt;GENERAL C. KICKLIGHTER&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC JAMES FISHER&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC ROGER KING&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC ANITA MINNIEFIELD&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC MARTHA SMYTH&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC DIANE WATERS&lt;/pe&gt; For THE HISTORY CHANNEL Supervising Producer &lt;pe&gt;ELYSE MIRANDA&lt;/pe&gt; Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;CHARLIE MADAY&lt;/pe&gt; This program was produced by Lou Reda Productions for The History Channel &lt;da&gt;1999&lt;/da&gt; A&amp;E Television Networks (c) All Rights Reserved. HISTORYCHANNEL.COM A LOU REDA PRODUCTION H THE HISTORY CHANNEL WHERE THE PAST COMES ALIVE&lt;/st&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;END TRANSCRIPT&lt;/p&gt;rent outfits that were low in men, [00:42:15]we knew the infantry was taking very heavy casualties. Ah, we had infantry [00:42:20]on the west, who were assigned the artillery. It was like [00:42:25]God came down and said, "You will live." We spontaneously formed a circle [00:42:30]like a ring around the roses and chanted, "We're gonna make it, we're [00:42:35]gonna make it."&lt;/pa&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:42:40]On August 31st, the North Koreans [00:42:45]gathered all the strength they had left and flung it against the thin, wavering UN line. [00:42:50]Their courage was unquestioned, their tactics a disaster. [00:42:55]In a seesaw battle over the next week with breakthroughs often inches away [00:43:00]and &lt;pe&gt;Walker&lt;/pe&gt; forced to consider a general withdrawal, [00:43:05]the Northerners broke themselves on withering UN firepower.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[00:43:10]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;vo&gt;&lt;sp&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/sp&gt; [00:43:15]The enemy had snapped the overstretched rubbberband of men, food, guns and [00:43:20]ammunitions stretching back north. For now, the &lt;pl&gt;Pusan&lt;/pl&gt; Perimeter [00:43:25]had held. [00:43:30]And miraculously, there began to be whispers of a brilliant new offensive [00:43:35]operation being put together personally by America's legendary God of War, [00:43:40]&lt;pe&gt;Douglas MacArthur&lt;/pe&gt;.&lt;/vo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;st&gt;THE KOREAN WAR FIRE &amp; ICE Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;Lou Reda&lt;/pe&gt; Produced By &lt;pe&gt;Mort Zimmerman&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Vincent Mondillo&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Tracey A. Connor&lt;/pe&gt; Written By &lt;pe&gt;Norman Stahl&lt;/pe&gt; with &lt;pe&gt;Joseph Alexander&lt;/pe&gt; and &lt;pe&gt;Rod Paschall&lt;/pe&gt; Edited By &lt;pe&gt;Tracey A. Connor&lt;/pe&gt; Executive in Charge of Production &lt;pe&gt;Sammy Jackson&lt;/pe&gt; Narrated By &lt;pe&gt;Edward Herrmann&lt;/pe&gt; Post Production Supervisor &lt;pe&gt;Paul Lewis&lt;/pe&gt; Special Thanks To &lt;pe&gt;Col. Richard T. Poore&lt;/pe&gt;, USMC (Ret.) &lt;pe&gt;Mr. Martin Russ&lt;/pe&gt; The Korean Society &lt;pe&gt;Col. Warren Wiedhahn&lt;/pe&gt; Military Historical Tours &lt;pe&gt;Joseph Calabria&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Cono Lombardi&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Corp. A.F. Kiviehan&lt;/pe&gt; Chapter Of The Korean War Veterans Assoc. &lt;pe&gt;Col. Michael F. Monigan&lt;/pe&gt; Marine Corps Photo Archives &lt;pe&gt;M.E. Englander&lt;/pe&gt; Naval Media Center U.S. Navy Public Affairs &lt;pe&gt;Adm. Thomas Jurkowsky&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Lt. Scott Allen&lt;/pe&gt; Special Consultant &lt;pe&gt;Gen. Edwin H. Simmons&lt;/pe&gt; Archival Resources U.S. Marine Corps U.S. Navy U.S. Army The National Archives M-25 Productions Lou Reda Archives Department of Defense &lt;pe&gt;Bill Barr&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Robert Melhorn&lt;/pe&gt; For Lou Reda Productions Graphics &lt;pe&gt;Paul Lewis&lt;/pe&gt; Map Design &lt;pe&gt;Matt Stahl&lt;/pe&gt; Trancripts &lt;pe&gt;Sharon Stahl&lt;/pe&gt; Office Coordinators &lt;pe&gt;Alison Dorshimer&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Jeanette Reyes&lt;/pe&gt; Duplication &lt;pe&gt;Tom Schinstine&lt;/pe&gt; Archives &lt;pe&gt;Chris Futrics&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;John McCullough&lt;/pe&gt; Production Assistants &lt;pe&gt;Lou Reda II&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Mark Tergesen&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;Stacy L. Schiomann&lt;/pe&gt; Executive Administration &lt;pe&gt;Mrs. Timmie Reda&lt;/pe&gt; Assistant To Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;Scott Reda&lt;/pe&gt; Opening Title Design &lt;pe&gt;Lauri Salladay&lt;/pe&gt; So! much design Additional Elements &lt;pe&gt;Rob Cazin&lt;/pe&gt; So! much design Music by PROMUSIC Audio EFX Design &lt;pe&gt;Scott Delaney&lt;/pe&gt; Audio Plus Video Additional Music by Swing'N Dixie &lt;pe&gt;Parke Frankenfield&lt;/pe&gt; Orchestra Edited on MEDIA 100 MEDIA This program produced in &lt;pl&gt;Easton, Pennsylvania&lt;/pl&gt; at the Lou Reda Studios &lt;da&gt;1950&lt;/da&gt;-&lt;da&gt;1953&lt;/da&gt; &lt;pl&gt;UNITED STATES OF AMERICA&lt;/pl&gt; &lt;da&gt;2000&lt;/da&gt;-&lt;da&gt;2003&lt;/da&gt; COMMEMORATION 50 ANIVERSARY OF THE KOREAN WAR COMMEMORATION 50th Anniversary of the Korean War Commemoration 50th Anniversary of the Korean War Commemoration Committee &lt;pe&gt;GENERAL C. KICKLIGHTER&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC JAMES FISHER&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC ROGER KING&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC ANITA MINNIEFIELD&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC MARTHA SMYTH&lt;/pe&gt; &lt;pe&gt;LTC DIANE WATERS&lt;/pe&gt; For THE HISTORY CHANNEL Supervising Producer &lt;pe&gt;ELYSE MIRANDA&lt;/pe&gt; Executive Producer &lt;pe&gt;CHARLIE MADAY&lt;/pe&gt; This program was produced by Lou Reda Productions for The History Channel </field>
      <field name="copyright_message">Copyright 2008 A&amp;E Television Networks</field>
      <field name="countryfilter">US CA AR BS BZ BM BO BR CL CO CR DO EC GT HN JM MX NI PY PE PR LC MF TT UY VE AF AM AU AZ BH BN MM CN CK FJ GE GU HK IN ID IR IQ IL PS JP JO KZ KW KG LB MO MY MV FM MN NP NZ KP OM PK PG PH QA RU SA SG KR LK TW TJ TH TL TR TM AE VU VN YE DZ BW TD DJ EG ET GM GH KE LR MW MU MA NG SN SC ZA SZ UG ZM ZW AL AT BY BE BA BG HR CY CZ DK EE FI FR DE GR HU IS IE IT LV LI LT LU MK MT MD MC ME NL NO PL PT RO RS SK SI ES SE CH UA GB UZ</field>
      <field name="digital_publication_date">2011-10-03</field>
      <field name="digital_publication_date_facet">2011-10-03T12:52:11Z</field>
      <field name="digital_publisher">Alexander Street Press</field>
      <field name="digital_publisher_place">Alexandria, VA</field>
      <field name="discipline_subject_hierarchy">History|American History|Post-war Era (1945-1960)</field>
      <field name="discipline_subject_hierarchy">American Studies|American History|Post-war Era (1945-1960)</field>
      <field name="discipline_tertiary_subject_hierarchy">History|American History|Post-war Era (1945-1960)</field>
      <field name="discipline_tertiary_subject_hierarchy">American Studies|American History|Post-war Era (1945-1960)</field>
      <field name="display_order">0</field>
      <field name="document_type">Documentary</field>
      <field name="dorp_id">1000993009</field>
      <field name="downloadable">0</field>
      <field name="duration">2700</field>
      <field name="eba_price">131.25</field>
      <field name="exclude_from_release">0</field>
      <field name="format">Video</field>
      <field name="general_subject">Military strategy</field>
      <field name="general_subject_hierarchy">Military strategy</field>
      <field name="google_exposure">true</field>
      <field name="group_id">1785647</field>
      <field name="group_real_title">making of a bloodbath</field>
      <field name="groupfilter">history</field>
      <field name="groupfilter">american-studies</field>
      <field name="grouping_path">Making of a Bloodbath</field>
      <field name="historical_event">Korean Conflict, 1950-1953</field>
      <field name="historical_event_hierarchy">11950070019530700*Korean Conflict, 1950-1953</field>
      <field name="history_era">Post-war Era (19451960)</field>
      <field name="history_era_facet">3945*Post-war Era (19451960)</field>
      <field name="inbound_link_id">454968</field>
      <field name="join_id">person|769024</field>
      <field name="join_id">organization|32731</field>
      <field name="join_id">person|275491</field>
      <field name="language_of_edition">English</field>
      <field name="marc_id">ASP1000993009/ahiv</field>
      <field name="marc_id">ASP1000993009/vast</field>
      <field name="object_id">bibliographic_entity|video_work|1785647</field>
      <field name="object_subtype">video_work</field>
      <field name="object_type">bibliographic_entity</field>
      <field name="organization_role_facet">ae television networks*A&amp;E Television Networks|32731</field>
      <field name="organization_role_facet">ae television networks*A&amp;E Television Networks|32731|Publisher</field>
      <field name="original_language">English</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">zimmerman mort*Zimmerman, Mort|769024</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">zimmerman mort*Zimmerman, Mort|769024|Producer</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">herrmann edward*Herrmann, Edward|275491</field>
      <field name="person_role_facet">herrmann edward*Herrmann, Edward|275491|Narrator</field>
      <field name="place_discussed">Korea (Historical Place)</field>
      <field name="place_subject_hierarchy">Asia|Korea (Historical Place)</field>
      <field name="processed_timestamp">2014-07-18T06:53:35Z</field>
      <field name="producer">Mort Zimmerman</field>
      <field name="producer_facet">zimmerman mort*Zimmerman, Mort|769024</field>
      <field name="producer_select_term">Zimmerman, Mort</field>
      <field name="product_code">AHIV</field>
      <field name="product_code">HISC</field>
      <field name="product_code">VASS</field>
      <field name="publication_date">1999</field>
      <field name="publication_date_facet">1999</field>
      <field name="publication_date_sort">19999999</field>
      <field name="publication_place_hierarchy">North and Central America|United States|New York|New York, NY</field>
      <field name="publication_type">Monograph</field>
      <field name="publisher">A&amp;E Television Networks</field>
      <field name="publisher_facet">ae television networks*A&amp;E Television Networks|32731</field>
      <field name="publisher_place">New York, NY</field>
      <field name="publisher_select_term">A&amp;E Television Networks</field>
      <field name="real_title">Making of a Bloodbath</field>
      <field name="real_title_sort">making of a bloodbath</field>
      <field name="release_date">1999</field>
      <field name="release_year_facet">1999</field>
      <field name="series_notation">1</field>
      <field name="series_number">1</field>
      <field name="speaker_narrator_facet">Herrmann, Edward</field>
      <field name="speaker_performer_facet">Herrmann, Edward</field>
      <field name="subcommunityfilter">americapostwar</field>
      <field name="suppress_eba">0</field>
      <field name="territorial_restrictions_whitelist">229</field>
      <field name="thumbnail_id">1000993009</field>
      <field name="timecode">1000993009-1-00:00:00-00:45:00</field>
      <field name="unitaccess">AHIV-V1</field>
      <field name="unitaccess">VAST-BF</field>
      <field name="unitaccess">PVST-BF</field>
      <field name="unitaccess_collection">AHIV-V1|American History in Video</field>
      <field name="unitaccess_collection">VAST-BF|VAST: Academic Video Online</field>
      <field name="unitaccess_collection">PVST-BF|Public Library Video Online</field>
      <field name="video_narrator">Edward Herrmann</field>
      <field name="video_narrator_facet">herrmann edward*Herrmann, Edward|275491</field>
      <field name="video_narrator_select_term">Herrmann, Edward</field>
      <field name="video_series">Korean War</field>
      <field name="video_thumbnail">180</field>
      <field name="error_msg">'0000' date found for creation_date.</field>
      <field name="error_code">C0722</field>
      <field name="error_msg">Cardinality error: more than one value encountered for Lazr Sort Year: 1999,1999.</field>
   </doc>
</add>
